Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I so testify for you. I knew that 3 more times, and can I testify for you? I sorta like you, that I do it all, and I'm gonna find you scared to do. I'm not, as long as you joking.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Long as you dreaming about me, ain't no problem. I don't got nobody just with you right now. For the truth, I look better under you. I can't lose When I'm with you. How can I snooze and miss the moment?
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: You're just too important, nobody do body like you do your job. In the drops I ride with you, I feel like Scarface. Like the whites with the vibe, I be amazing.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Take this argument back up to my place. Sex remind you I'm not violent on your day one. We had, yeah. It was magic, yeah. Smash and grab, yeah. Nasty habits take a hole when you're not here. Ain't a home when you're not. I'll grow when you're not, you know what I'm saying? I'll kill yours when I kill ya.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: How can I snooze and miss the moment? You're just too important, nobody do body like you do. How can I snooze and miss the moment? You're just too important. Nobody do body like you do, you're good.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I ain' blaming on me, and you the main one time? I ain' blaming me when I'm the main one?
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: How can I snooze and miss the moment? You just do a boy, nobody will bite you like you do. I keep doing those What's wrong with you? How can I snooze and miss the moment?
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Nobody, nobody like you do, you're good.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: It's enough why I can lose it.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I can't relate to desperation.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I give a fuck. Or on vacation
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Stop getting enough perfume on the floor.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: brand new order for ya.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: This is that sweet, I guess so.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'm working late, cause I'm a singer Oh, it looks so cute. Wrapped around my finger on twisted humor.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Come and get this pollen. Goodbye, your eggs, don't do it for ya. Walking and drinking, drink it for you. I perfuming it for ya.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: the lightning to low.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: They can slave to be alone.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: We unknowns.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Is it that sweet, I guess so?
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: That send me a special.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I've been on my own for long enough Maybe you can show me how to love Baby
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'm going through a drawer
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: You don't even have to do too much You can tell me I'm just a touch.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: B.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'm a color.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: The city's cold and empty.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: No one's around to judge me. I can't see clearly when you're
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Oh, I'm blinded by the light. No, I can't sleep in it till I feel your
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: And I… Oh my god!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'm running out of time, cause I can see the sunlight up the sky, so I ain't throw in overdrive, baby.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: It is cold and empty. No one's around to judge me. I can see clearly when you're not gonna lie.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'm blinded by the light. No, I can sleep in it till I feel the old.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Let's go I can never say it on the floor.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'll say!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: No, I get sleeping into the billions.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'm blinded by delight, though I can sleep in, till I feel your attention.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: You let my heart up When the rest of me is down.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: You are new and charming, even when you're not around.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: If there are boundaries, I will try to knock them down. I'm latching all day. Now I know what I have found.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I swear the door.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I wanna lock you, you're the
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I jump in my space.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I won't be born again
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: No, no!
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: I'm showing captured Got me wrapped up in your touch.
Audio shared by 100xEngineers: Hold me tight within your clutches. How do you do it? You got me losing your breath.
100xEngineers: Hi folks, good evening, good afternoon.
100xEngineers: Based on wherever you are, joining this session from, how are you guys feeling? How is the overall vibe?
100xEngineers: First of all, this is the combined session for, I think, everybody. I was expecting slightly more number of people, but I think people are joining right now, so anyways, I don't want to wait.
100xEngineers: And we'll start.
100xEngineers: But let's start with a quick wipe check. How are you guys feeling?
100xEngineers: How's your weekend going? Tired, Dave.
100xEngineers: 99 by 10.
100xEngineers: 10, 10, 9.5. Awesome, that's great. That's great.
100xEngineers: Wow, Kunan is at a 99.
100xEngineers: I wanna have the same thing, Kunar, what you're having.
100xEngineers: To get a 99 vibe, but interestingly, I, I also want to…
100xEngineers: just share, like, a few things here. One is about, what we're gonna do today in this lecture, and also what is the plan for the next two weeks. And I shared this in yesterday's session, but with the code track. I just, like, maybe reiterate on that right now. First, let me set the agenda.
100xEngineers: Awful.
100xEngineers: This particular session. Let me…
100xEngineers: Let me share my screen, just give me one sec.
100xEngineers: Can anybody see my screen?
100xEngineers: Awesome, thanks.
100xEngineers: Yeah, I think this lecture will also help you to, like, I would say, set the next milestone.
100xEngineers: And the reason why I want to do this combined is because the principles which I will be sharing today, in fact, we won't be just, like, covering theory. I have a practical aspect of it, which I have added here. So, irrespective of whether you are joining from the code track or no code track, you should be able to, like, have something by the end of this lecture. And the goal for this lecture and the agenda is this. First of all, the lecture is about the second interface.
100xEngineers: We all have built our first interface in the last
100xEngineers: lecture, which was the UI, and I hope now everything is clear. I'll come back to the diagram once again, but…
100xEngineers: We started our journey understanding that what all systems we need, on a higher level, in order for us to, like, build better solutions,
100xEngineers: the first thing we need to know is what exactly we are building, right? And if I have to go back here, we had our whole journey about…
100xEngineers: this module, how this module is gonna be structured. I know some people are feeling confused right now, and it's completely okay, it's a new module, new way of learning. There's a lot of things that are happening, and we are also, like, working on a couple of interesting parts for all of you, so I think that'll be, something exciting for all of you coming for the next two weeks. So, a lot of things happening, and
100xEngineers: And the way we have started it, just to reiterate.
100xEngineers: Understanding what to build, this is where the discovery skill comes in. So, once we have the idea of
100xEngineers: what exactly we're gonna solve as a problem, because this is an important skill to learn. And then, from week 2 to week 10, which is the next part, is gonna be focused on exactly how we're gonna build that thing, whatever we have decided to build.
100xEngineers: And the first and foremost principle which I shared yesterday is that
100xEngineers: even before designing a system, we need to know what are the inputs for this system, and what are the desired output for it. So we did a quick exercise yesterday, and we took an example of our friend Arav, the same
100xEngineers: story, and I basically had this document, which I'll share with all of you. This is the…
100xEngineers: This is the same document which I will be using, so if somebody has forgot about the example and the story, I would recommend you to maybe quickly take a look. The story is…
100xEngineers: everything, you can find it here in the discovery document. What was the observation, what was our subject, and everything. So what I wanted to showcase you and throughout this series is that how we take an observation and convert into a full-fledged application while learning everything from post-principles.
100xEngineers: So I'll be taking an example of this today as well. You can feel free to use your own observation, and you can apply the same principles here.
100xEngineers: back yesterday, like, we discussed this was the hypothesis, and we figured out there are some inputs and outputs we need, and based on that, we have designed a simple, interface, which we decided we're gonna use code, because I was teaching code guys, and we basically ended up building a simple interface that can take an input and give some output back. That is what we ended up building. So…
100xEngineers: we figured out the first part, which is a very core part of everything, and I hope, like, now everybody who is on this call have some clarity, and if you don't have clarity, don't worry, we'll basically have some catch-up sessions with all of you guys, and we are trying to, like, also, like, address the feedback which we have received, so…
100xEngineers: we'll try to, like, like, make sure that everybody by end of this week will have clarity on how do you identify the right inputs and the outputs, and once you have that, this is where the journey which has begun. So, we started with deterministic part of it, because we realized that
100xEngineers: the system design and building any kind of AI tool is not just
100xEngineers: building a wrapper around LLM, it has, like, a whole, world around it. So, deterministic, probabilistic, and human in the loop, we are starting with the deterministic world, which is based on rules. The rules that converts into zeros and ones, the binaries that your machine executes. And in the first part of the deterministic system.
100xEngineers: what we learned, last time, that every system, like the chat GPT, is built off smaller systems.
100xEngineers: Which made this entire thing possible. And all those smaller systems share a boundary, and this boundary is known as the interface. This is the medium
100xEngineers: where these different systems talk to each other. So we had the whole interface journey, and this is what we… we learned, that when we use ChatGPT, it's not the same app, it's the…
100xEngineers: app which uses multiple subsystems, and these systems combined together use different interfaces to talk to each other, and that's how, like, we can see an app working in front of us. So the goal is also to
100xEngineers: like, break down something like ChatGPT, and at the end of the next two weeks, the goal I was telling you, all of you, is to…
100xEngineers: that all of you should be able to build a mini version of ChatGPT for yourself, right? And or maybe, like, something which is slightly more specific. But at least, like, this is something which all of you can build, even if you don't do anything and just watch the lectures.
100xEngineers: This is one of the primary agenda, to understand,
100xEngineers: Now, where we are at, at this point in our journey, we covered the user interfaces yesterday. This was the first interface.
100xEngineers: Now the…
100xEngineers: The problem with yesterday's, I would say the output was that this output is great, we have built a front-end for people who are in the code track.
100xEngineers: we saw, like, how we can use Python to build simple interfaces using the text box, the chat, and we end up going to the chat. People who are in no-code, you guys must have seen how do you build the mock-up UIs using Lovable. That becomes, like, one of the ways, and initially, it might seem that it's a more simpler way to, like, build UI, but eventually, we all will converge into the
100xEngineers: I would say, The overall system design, where the…
100xEngineers: Principles will remain the same, and you can use the same principles, but with different tools, and you can design anything there. But coming back to it, like, we have designed this part, and now we are moving one step ahead in our journey. So, in order for us to, like, design everything which is here.
100xEngineers: we need to start with the first thing, right? And this is where we are setting today. This is the second interface in our journey. So what we're gonna learn today is
100xEngineers: what is exactly an API, and I'll teach you through
100xEngineers: an interactive exercise. We'll share an exercise with all of you,
100xEngineers: I have already uploaded this on LMS as well, but I'll come to this exercise in next 30 to 35 minutes. But before that, I'll share
100xEngineers: some bit about this API, because this is the most confusing term among, like, a lot of non-coders and people who are not used to of building applications, because people use APIs for each and everything. So we'll clarify what are the things which is useful for us, the terms.
100xEngineers: how do we design one API? What are the core components? So, by end of this session, every single person who is here
100xEngineers: you should be able to, like, have the skills which you can use to design your own APIs. And the next week, both for code and no code.
100xEngineers: you guys will build your own APIs, and finally connect the pieces of the backend and front-end. So, this is what we are aiming for by the next week. The next lecture, we'll have our backend ready, our API ready, and we'll also have our LLM connection ready. I'll show you a glimpse of all of these things, because right now, for some of you, it might seem like a theoretical lecture, which I'm taking, or maybe which we have taken, so…
100xEngineers: The reason which I shared yesterday as well, that this is not theory, what I'm showing you on this diagram. This is the legit system architecture of a lot of applications, if I have to abstract it out. And the reason why we spent so much time here is because once you get clarity on what are the systems you're building, where are the boundaries, and what interfaces are there, it just becomes the part of implementation. I'll show you, like, how easy the implementation is, but
100xEngineers: That is the part which we will be doing. So, by end of, like, next lecture, you will have a full-fledged system, which you can use to
100xEngineers: build user interfaces, connect these user interfaces with the backend, use an API, connect it with an LLM, and after that, we'll start a database. So this will come as a lecture
100xEngineers: beyond the practical implementation of API. So… That's a goal. And,
100xEngineers: Let me address the second part of the equation. I'll come back to the questions, but the second part is
100xEngineers: the journey, right? And I read right now on the chat, some people are confused, some people are overwhelmed, some people are thinking that this is too slow, and this is all normal response, by the way. Like, someone who is having
100xEngineers: a similar response, whether you feel that the things which we are sharing is slow, or maybe something which is, like, too complicated, some people might feel this is, like, overwhelming. All of these are completely fine, and this is a part of learning,
100xEngineers: Andrew Uberman mentioned this. Neuroplasticity only happens when you face the errors, right? Those errors, those struggles, when you feel, that is where the learning happens, right? Exactly, so…
100xEngineers: It's okay, we are planning to do a follow-up session as well, TJ, so… Don't worry about it.
100xEngineers: But by end of this session, you'll have, like, a full clarity, and by the end of the next session, as I said,
100xEngineers: if you… if you… if anybody still not be able to, like, build the system which I have drawn on this diagram by the end of, like, next lecture, I'm happy to, like, sit on a call personally with the people who are facing problems, right? That's the word which I can give you. And that's the kind of, like, dedication which I also want to, like, be transparent about, right? The reason why this entire business I have been, like.
100xEngineers: Running from the last 3 years, and we are still
100xEngineers: doing only, I would say, limited number of people, and not turning this into, like, something which we can do, right? I don't know how many of you know about this, but the reason why I started 100X Engineers is not just to build another ed tech business, is because I genuinely care about
100xEngineers: solving the education problem, right? And, maybe sometimes it doesn't come across in these sessions, like, because I haven't shared a lot about, like, the vision and mission, and that's something which I will save at the end of… for the end of the lecture. But,
100xEngineers: The intention here is actually to provide
100xEngineers: the best education which we can do as per whatever resources we have available. But having said that, if any of you are facing any kind of issues, and I think, as I said, like, my personal agenda is that every single person who is here on this call, who's attending, who is serious, who is diligent, who is working and building the assignments.
100xEngineers: by end of the next two weeks, if you're not able to, like, build what we have decided to build, I'm happy to, like, sit on one-on-one call with you and make sure that you actually learn those things. Without that, I won't leave you. Without that, like, I won't be able to, like, even, like.
100xEngineers: send you…
100xEngineers: For the graduation, because I know that that's… everything which we're gonna do after this point won't make sense if you guys can't build these basic elements. So, yeah, don't worry about that. Like, I think some people had those things. Now, apart from that, there was another,
100xEngineers: thing which I want to address here is that, yes, the beginning part of this module is supposed to be like this, for some people who are feeling slightly overwhelmed, slightly confused, or maybe who are feeling that this is, like, too easy for them.
100xEngineers: Because, based on your past experience of the technology, what you have used, it could vary. And, for some people, as you said, like, who are, like, confused, you are confused because
100xEngineers: We are running 3 different…
100xEngineers: threads parallelly, right now, for this module. Module 1 was, like, pretty basic, easy, because it was, like, a starting one, but
100xEngineers: this is the level 2 of 100x, right? Where we are trying to teach you every single thing that we have learned with the last 50,000 plus students that I have worked with.
100xEngineers: In my journey of last 10 years of building software, and with all the instructors and Sridev's journey, and everything, we are trying to compile and just transfer all the information to you in the next, 2 to 3 months. And it's gonna be overwhelming, it's gonna be difficult, and sometimes some things might not make sense to you, sometimes, like, you might feel that it's, like.
100xEngineers: like, too easy, and sometimes you feel as confusing, but all of these are completely okay, and the way how I would recommend you to…
100xEngineers: Like, solve this part.
100xEngineers: A, just be very clear about your North Star, right? One thing which…
100xEngineers: why we started this entire journey with the discovery first is because every single person should have a North Star, which means that, what are you aiming for for the next two weeks? And we have designed this section into different milestones. What are we trying to build in the next two weeks? So if you have that clarity, do send us a message. I'm gonna, like.
100xEngineers: Tell my team, we basically work
100xEngineers: like, on a weekend at this time, and anyways, like, I work on weekends, like, mostly. But I'll try to, like, take the help of my team, and we'll go through, like, each and every person's response, right? If you have any kind of, I would say.
100xEngineers: confusion regarding the sessions, regarding the concepts, send everything. Like, whatever your feedback is. I know, like, there are a couple of people who have already sent the feedback, we are working on that, and I think you'll receive the updates from us. But even if you have any kind of feedback about
100xEngineers: Not able to, like, start your journey.
100xEngineers: just send us everything, like, if you are not comfortable sharing it on the main channel, you can directly DM me or my team. I would, like, go through all of them. Because this is the most important part, having clarity on what you are building for the next two weeks. This is where the discovery comes in, this is the first thread of it.
100xEngineers: It's also, like, important to understand what is worth building, and that is why this session, the first session was basically focused on that. The second thread here is about once you know what is worth building.
100xEngineers: the concept and the principles. So this is what I am taking whenever I come… we do the combined sessions for both code and no code. We'll share the principles. Like, last principle which we had about the interface, we learned about how interface works, and I hope now you can
100xEngineers: relate to that example, and we'll take that example in every lecture, in everything which we're gonna build, and hopefully, in the next couple of weeks, you'll see that how the principle that we have took from that interface journey is shaping each and everything.
100xEngineers: This is gonna be…
100xEngineers: a common part. Here, I won't do a lot of execution, because the audience is going to be mixed code and no code. So for the execution part, we'll have a separate session, which is where we separate the track of the code and no code. With code, we'll use the Python. For no code, we'll use tools like Lavable, NN, and, like, more things. So NN is coming the next week, by the way.
100xEngineers: So…
100xEngineers: that's where we do the execution part. And all of these three things running parallelly can make some people overwhelmed, and can have some doubts, and I know this is something which, is gonna be… is there. Things won't get easy.
100xEngineers: something which I'm declaring right now. Things won't get easy. It will slightly get even more overwhelming as we progress from this point onwards, but that is about what we have chosen to learn, right? And this is…
100xEngineers: this is overwhelming, this is difficult, that is why this is valuable. Otherwise, everyone would have learned this, everyone would have figured this part out. So, it's completely fine, as I said again, and we'll come back to this, but I hope, like, now you understand that these three threads gonna be there, it's gonna be running for the next two weeks.
100xEngineers: And at the end of this.
100xEngineers: journey, the journey of, like, us building a whole system, which we can reason from first principle and build from first principle, is that it will give you a power
100xEngineers: That you can look at any problem statement in your life, in someone else's business, Anywhere on the internet.
100xEngineers: And you can design a system, and you can build a hypothesis which you can falsify, and you can take that hypothesis, convert it into an MVP, validate that MVP, build and design a whole system, design the inputs and output, and deploy it on a URL which you can share with the world. Having this knowledge, having this understanding and power used to take 4 years, 5 years, sometimes
100xEngineers: like, 6 to 10 years of time for people. Like, if you ask me, like, I've spent 4 years learning computer science engineering just to learn how to, like, do all these things.
100xEngineers: And that's also, like, a thing, right? Like, it's powerful, it's interesting, but it's also intimidating sometimes, so I completely understand that part. But this is what we're aiming to do, right? And it's, as I said, like.
100xEngineers: If you do this, you have an insane amount of leverage.
100xEngineers: And this leverage is not equivalent to the white coding leverage, because yes, you can do all of these things with white coding as well, but what we are trying to do here is to, like, learn the principles behind it, so that even when you have to wipe code, you know exactly, like, what are the underlying systems are there, and you can… you can still guide the LLM, so you…
100xEngineers: You basically get the promotion from
100xEngineers: As we say in the current world, from whiteboarding to agentic engineering, right? So, these are two important parts about the next two weeks, so I hope, like, you get the picture that where we are moving, and what we are gonna start with today.
100xEngineers: I'll take the questions in the next 30 minutes, I'll…
100xEngineers: Finish up the part, we'll share the exercise, and then we'll… we'll take the questions.
100xEngineers: Actually, let me use the whiteboard itself.
100xEngineers: I prefer whiteboard for… This kind of discussion.
100xEngineers: This is what we have built right now, and to be very specific.
100xEngineers: I'll take an example of what we have done with,
100xEngineers: code, but it's gonna be relevant for even no code, because I'm just using the interface right now.
100xEngineers: Actually… So, this is the simple interface.
100xEngineers: Which we have built in the last code lecture, so I'll take this as an example on my whiteboard.
100xEngineers: This is one of the basic interfaces that we had built, and now, what…
100xEngineers: my problem statement was, just to summarize back, this is my hypothesis, that I believe
100xEngineers: Ambitious early career professionals in urban India who are AI-aware but have no ship proof are stuck because they lack method to convert broad AI possibility into one specific scoped workflow worth solving. If we provide
100xEngineers: A structured workflow diagnosis system, followed by a guided build sprint.
100xEngineers: then at least 60% of active students will identify one real user, map one repeated workflow, build a working AI-assisted version, and present a credible demo or a case study within 90 days. That's my hypothesis, that's what I built, what I think based on the observation which I've seen across, like, thousands of students.
100xEngineers: And I want to, like, prove this hypothesis, whether, like, can I build it, can I validate it? I've already spoken to people, so validation is done. Now.
100xEngineers: what I need here is the… first, to design the whole system is the input and output. In this case, my input
100xEngineers: was what we came yesterday to a conclusion. We asked people, like, what could be the input, but one of the input here is.
100xEngineers: This system should take the explanation of
100xEngineers: a workflow. In this case, Arav is a business analyst, so what Ara would do, maybe explain what he does, and what are the repeated tasks in his day. Maybe just, like, go about it, and we also define that what kind of input we're gonna take. We're gonna restrict it to text right now, because we don't want it to…
100xEngineers: Oh, I would say…
100xEngineers: make slightly more complicated on the day one. We start with text, and then we can add more elements to it. But as of now, this is what I expect as the input. Output is going to be very specific, a plan, not the whole thing, because even if I give everything to RF, it'll still be the same thing what RF can generate from anywhere. But this is…
100xEngineers: specific thing, there's a written plan, which will identify the repeatable patterns and create a faster AI-setter design workflow based on what Arav is doing in his job.
100xEngineers: And it's… the output is also gonna be a text.
100xEngineers: in my understanding, if I have a problem statement like this, and if I can take an input like this and generate an output, and I can show this output to Arav, and now Arav can take this output and take a plan and start, like, building this workflow.
100xEngineers: it's still a valuable piece of technology, which I can build and I can focus my time on. I would still use a human in the loop to make sure that I take follow-up and I coach ARF and do all of those things, but having a tool like this definitely helps, right?
100xEngineers: So this is what I yesterday discussed, and we had, like, multiple choices to do this. Like, we can use maybe an interface like this, where I can take…
100xEngineers: the input workflow from Arav, where he describes everything, and I can show him the output. Or we can do a chat interface, where, just like what ChatGB does, we can do that as well. This is how the chat, by the way, looks like in the radio part.
100xEngineers: I keep, right now…
100xEngineers: This one only, but you can… you can think of, like, whatever interface you have designed. Now, for people who have designed it on Lavable, you had slightly more fancy UI system with you, so you can maybe insert your UI here.
100xEngineers: And this is where both the tracks are sitting here. We have our system, which can interact with somebody, and we can, like, add things there. It can give us some output.
100xEngineers: Now, this is the time where we introduce our second interface, and the way how I want to introduce this second interface is because… or is the way where I will start asking you some questions, and hopefully we'll get to a conclusion together, that this is the best way for us to design this interface.
100xEngineers: Actually, let me back… let me get back to the same exercise.
100xEngineers: which I have shared.
100xEngineers: to design the system. The exercises…
100xEngineers: I am a machine which is now a well-proven fact. I hope everybody knows this by this lecture, and
100xEngineers: what I want all of you to do is to… you want me to… you… I want you guys to…
100xEngineers: Make me… will give you… a weather report.
100xEngineers: And what I can do is I can… I can perform the same steps, but…
100xEngineers: just think about it, in this case, I am also a specific Weather Reporting Service.
100xEngineers: This is a better description for me.
100xEngineers: just like how there are a lot of other apps are there on the internet, think of me like a machine which is sitting on AWS server, and this is the goal here.
100xEngineers: Of this exercise.
100xEngineers: You want… you guys need to…
100xEngineers: Fetch the weather report or weather details.
100xEngineers: Of any city, whatever you feel like. And, you need to get the details out of me.
100xEngineers: We'll start the exercise.
100xEngineers: I'll start it in… Actually, I'll start right now.
100xEngineers: And, you need to be specific. Don't make the same mistakes which you made in the last exercise, where everybody was typing things. So, I won't, give you hints right now.
100xEngineers: I'll stop saying things. If you have any questions, you can ask me right now.
100xEngineers: If you don't have any questions, we'll start the exercise.
100xEngineers: Just to repeat one more time, the exercise is…
100xEngineers: I'm a weather reporting service machine, I'll act like that, and you need to make me give you a weather report.
100xEngineers: My interface is whiteboard. Actually, my interface is this chat, sorry. The interface is chat, let me write this on, thanks for…
100xEngineers: The interface is Zoom chat.
100xEngineers: Machine is stuck because machine was getting a lot of information.
100xEngineers: Without any clear direction.
100xEngineers: Okay, I'll break the character, because…
100xEngineers: This is still confusing for both, for a machine as well as for a human being, and you guys don't need to write anything right now.
100xEngineers: And I'll reflect back on a very important exercise here, and I'll try to read all the answers, and I'll tell you, like, why exactly I didn't take any action, because let me show you this…
100xEngineers: the first message which I got, starting from…
100xEngineers: I think, let me scroll down.
100xEngineers: So John said, let us coordinate, and one person share the input. This is for the internal coordination, so definitely machine doesn't need to write anything for this. Then Sagar said, let's make a thread.
100xEngineers: Which is actually a smart approach, but I don't know who created a thread after this.
100xEngineers: Now, Saf wrote something interesting, and
100xEngineers: This is what Saf wrote here. Check weather from Google of Bangalore, summarize, make the report of Bangalore's weather data. Now, I'll tell you, like, if you write the same instructions.
100xEngineers: to a weather reporting service machine. Right now, you go to internet, and if you write all of those things, it won't give you anything.
100xEngineers: Dave, you want me to, like,
100xEngineers: Check this… this thing called… actually, let me do the… Open weather map.
100xEngineers: This is one of the surveys.
100xEngineers: You can go to this service, there's, like, multiple other services which are out there.
100xEngineers: So, this is how the service works. It gives you all the information, but if I do exact same thing, WhatsApp has given to me.
100xEngineers: Let's see if it gives the answer.
100xEngineers: It doesn't give the answer, by the way, right? So, one thing which I like… one person clarified what is the interface, and I gave the example exact, the interface is a chat, right?
100xEngineers: nobody tried to understand how the machine works. When I open this website, you guys can see that the interface has UI, and I need to, like, put some information here. So, this is something which I need to learn, right? How this machine works, and where I can put the input. So I need to, like, first understand what is the input, and how and where I can put this input.
100xEngineers: You guys already had the interface of chat?
100xEngineers: maybe putting the input would have helped here. So, something which…
100xEngineers: was lacking here, and I'll try to, like, put everything here. The first step, which machine didn't understand is where exactly the input is, is located.
100xEngineers: Is it,
100xEngineers: because based on Saf's answer, the input is supposed to be on Google, so the machine should go to a Google, but I already mentioned that I am a weather reporting service machine, so I might have the weather data already with me. So why are you asking me to go to a different service altogether?
100xEngineers: First of all, you don't know whether I talk to Google, because Google is a different service, I am a different service, I am a machine, Google is a machine, and I don't know, like, if I can talk to Google right now.
100xEngineers: So, this is the main part. I didn't have clarity on where to look for, or maybe, like, where is the right input.
100xEngineers: And even in the chat, there was, like, multiple answers, so machine could not focus on, so the first thing which I picked was this answer. The second part of this also was vague summarize, what to summarize.
100xEngineers: What are we surprising here?
100xEngineers: no clue. Machine will not give anything. Make a report of Bangalore's weather. Now, because I didn't have clarity on what should I summarize, and how do I talk to Google, and what is Google, because I'm a machine, the third won't make sense.
100xEngineers: Then, let me pick another one from… Vinothani, right? And,
100xEngineers: The reason I'm actually doing the exercise is also showing you a very interesting difference between a human psychology and
100xEngineers: writing deterministic software, or building deterministic application, because this is how we expect machines to perform, but machines don't perform this way. And only when you realize this gap, then only you can build better applications and solve the problems, because otherwise you will have the same problem. This is the second answer which I got from Vinothani, where
100xEngineers: they mentioned input, city.
100xEngineers: region, take the input, search against the Google data, service which has these data, send back the result.
100xEngineers: It's a good instruction for somebody who is building this API, or building this model, right, or maybe whatever app you want to create. But if I'm already a machine, right, imagine me as this company, and I'm, like, a machine sitting in one of their servers.
100xEngineers: All of this data won't make sense to me.
100xEngineers: Input city slash regional.
100xEngineers: If I copy this part, and if I paste it here, do you think this will give me any answer?
100xEngineers: It won't, right?
100xEngineers: The same thing here, like, the answers are vague. It's more like a template, you're teaching somebody how to build a system. So this instruction didn't work out at all. Sheikh said after this, focus on only messages in this thread.
100xEngineers: Then Shep Ali said, look, AUP longitude, latitude in a database.
100xEngineers: Specific answer, like the answer, but…
100xEngineers: for what, like, what are the… again, what are the inputs for which I will search the longitude and latitude in a database?
100xEngineers: that is missing here, right? And as a machine, I don't have this. Again, just to be really, I would say, brutal in front of all of you guys,
100xEngineers: I'll try to just, like, put everything in the search bar and see, like, if any of those things will make sense.
100xEngineers: And it won't, right?
100xEngineers: Mana said, give me a weather forecast for 1st June, Bangalore City. And this is, I think, the only relevant output which I got.
100xEngineers: After, like, the first few things, and so kudos to Manas, by the way, right? Who basically gave a very specific answer. Now, one thing which I didn't, like, explicitly mention is that, like, what is the input format that I receive?
100xEngineers: I definitely said that Zoom chat is the interface, but there is no…
100xEngineers: expectation, which we have discussed, of, like, how the… communication.
100xEngineers: should take place.
100xEngineers: And I purposefully didn't… I would say.
100xEngineers: described it, because I wanted to understand if people can figure out a way to communicate with this machine and figure out, like, how this machine works, right? Because most of us, when we open an app, we try to figure it out how this app works, by looking at the input, and we have a sense of intuition which works.
100xEngineers: So… which is something I was expecting, like, some people will figure out, yes, Zoom interfaces a chat, and you can put anything there, but…
100xEngineers: it's, again, being slightly more empathetic toward machine. How does this machine work, and, like, what are the things that I can communicate in which format? So that was also missing. This was, I would say, the format and the contract, right?
100xEngineers: is missing…
100xEngineers: how the communication should work. Although this is a really good answer, by the way, because if I put…
100xEngineers: if I put this, like, in a machine which can understand natural language.
100xEngineers: I think it can definitely give the answer, but unfortunately, I was acting as a weather reporting machine, not an AI machine, not the machine which has the AI capability, so I don't have the capability of understanding the whole natural language. So somebody has to first figure out how I communicate.
100xEngineers: how I take the input, how I give the output back, so…
100xEngineers: The first principle, which we discussed here, this is how, like, we design the systems, the deterministic system, and that's why I gave you a hint in the beginning, but I think only few people understood the hint.
100xEngineers: I am acting as a system, so you need to figure out what is the right input I should… getting, and what is the output I can expect.
100xEngineers: Now, in this case… Let me do a deep dive here.
100xEngineers: Give me a weather forecast for this. One more thing which is missing here is that weather means a lot of things.
100xEngineers: Weather means the temperature, the humidity.
100xEngineers: your, maybe the wind, etc. There's, like, so many components of weather, right? When you say weather forecast to a machine, what exactly you need? Like, do you need everything what I know? Do you need some things? Do you need specific parts?
100xEngineers: all of this thing becomes slightly difficult again. Like, we have not mentioned this anywhere.
100xEngineers: And I won't go through all the answers, but I hope you got the point which I'm trying to share here as a part, and
100xEngineers: Why you guys were not able to, like, do it successfully is because
100xEngineers: First and foremost thing, which is…
100xEngineers: I said, like, there's a missing communication channel. Just because you have the interface doesn't mean that you know how to communicate. Just because you can speak
100xEngineers: English doesn't mean that you have the etiquettes, and you can, like,
100xEngineers: let's speak to anyone, right? Like, there are people who don't know how to communicate in certain situations, and we all know that, right? So it's also, like, as important as understanding the interface, that how we should communicate with different systems and different machines. And this is the whole journey which is about, like, the second interface, right?
100xEngineers: What we're gonna do today, and this is for the rest of this entire module, is try to understand…
100xEngineers: How should we…
100xEngineers: build this communication layer, the set of rules which I know, if I'm talking to a machine, this is what it understands, this is how it takes the input.
100xEngineers: how the machine… slash service.
100xEngineers: takes the input.
100xEngineers: How it gives the output.
100xEngineers: I'm not talking only about the interface, but in what format, because I can definitely use Zoom chat to send anything. I can use this interface of text box to send anything here.
100xEngineers: But machine won't give me the right answer, right? I need to be very specific that what exactly I want, and what this machine can understand, and then need to find a right language.
100xEngineers: Which… which actually points us to, like, in order for us to, like, solve this problem of having a communication channel.
100xEngineers: Do you think we need something?
100xEngineers: What is the first thing in your head comes which we need, if you have to solve this first problem?
100xEngineers: Forget about everything else. If you just need to solve this one problem, how this communication should take place.
100xEngineers: And same, you have the Zoom interface, you have everything, you have the machine, which I gave you all the answers.
100xEngineers: What's the first thing which we need here?
100xEngineers: Rules are definitely there.
100xEngineers: But I'm not calling rules as a first thing, because it's kind of like, the implicit
100xEngineers: Maybe I'll keep it, like, on number 2.
100xEngineers: Rules are important, but what's the first thing even before rules you need?
100xEngineers: Yes, I think I love Girish answers. The way to communicate, right, because the problem we are trying to solve is how the communication should take place. If I don't understand the language, just take the same example. If I write gibberish here, will this give me an answer?
100xEngineers: No. I need to understand which language it works. If I write Hindi here, like, if I go maybe check, let's say…
100xEngineers: Bangalore in Hindi.
100xEngineers: This is how Bangalore is written in Hindi, and if I take this and paste it here.
100xEngineers: is actually, like, reading it right now, which means that it understands Hindi. But if I write it, like, in my coded language, which I don't know, like, maybe, like, or any language which this doesn't understand,
100xEngineers: Maybe I'll write it in binary.
100xEngineers: This is how I would write.
100xEngineers: the Bangloin binary. It doesn't understand binary language. So, just because it has the interface, doesn't mean that it can understand anything. So, first and foremost thing which I need to know is what language this machine understands.
100xEngineers: Now, every machine, by default, understands zeros and ones, but we have not designed all the machines in such a way that we can input zeros and ones, because humans cannot understand that.
100xEngineers: So we have to figure it out. The common convention is, yes, English is universal, so most machines can understand English, but what kind of English? Can we use this English, which is, like, a whole line, and can I put it back here?
100xEngineers: Will I get the answer?
100xEngineers: Right now, I'm not getting the answer there, by the way.
100xEngineers: So, it is English, same language.
100xEngineers: But what is… what is missing here? Can somebody help me to point out?
100xEngineers: And before that, I'll also, like, mention that, yes, the first thing is rules here, the language.
100xEngineers: And we have, let's say, defined for this machine.
100xEngineers: The language is, let's say, English.
100xEngineers: And after that, somebody sent me this, and I basically copied this and pasted it here, but it doesn't work.
100xEngineers: Why it doesn't work? What is missing?
100xEngineers: structure.
100xEngineers: Meaning?
100xEngineers: Syntax? Yes.
100xEngineers: we need to know all of this. We need to know the exact structure of… even just language, having a language or common language is not enough, right? Even if I know that this machine speaks language, or it can understand English language, I don't… I can't just, like, put any
100xEngineers: line like this. I need to be specific that what kind of input it understands, and this is where the rules comes in, right? And rules defines your
100xEngineers: Code part. What is a core part of every software?
100xEngineers: It takes input, it processes this input.
100xEngineers: And then it gives some output back. This is the core part of every software. You can map it, it's the first principle of software design.
100xEngineers: So, first and foremost thing which we need is
100xEngineers: We need to understand how this machine takes the input.
100xEngineers: What is the format?
100xEngineers: So, format of… input
100xEngineers: then what is the expectation of the output? Like, let's say, even if you figure out In this case.
100xEngineers: This is the input.
100xEngineers: And, if I don't understand what is going on here, which is actually, like, a lot of things, by the way, happening here on this screen.
100xEngineers: I won't be able to, like, make sense if I'm somebody who doesn't understand the interface here. So we need to know, like, what is the expectation? Maybe I'm somebody who's expecting text output, but I'm not getting as a text. So, we also need to make sure the format of the output, right? If you are putting in text, in this case.
100xEngineers: It's a type text. Is the output text? Is it graph?
100xEngineers: Is it gonna be voice? Is it gonna be visual? What is that?
100xEngineers: All of these things are important.
100xEngineers: Now, there is one more thing which is… which is, like, really important here is,
100xEngineers: the way we designed the exercise, I, by default, assume that everybody is on the Zoom chat, right? But what if somebody has missed this lecture?
100xEngineers: Let's say somebody has missed this lecture, and they are watching it
100xEngineers: Maybe as a recorded series or recorded lecture of the same part.
100xEngineers: For them, this interface won't work.
100xEngineers: How can they communicate to me?
100xEngineers: Because I'm still acting as a machine. This exercise actually won't make sense for a lot of pre-recorded, like, people who are watching this lecture as a pre-recorded series. But this is also something which we need to think about, right? How will somebody who is watching this as a pre-recorded lecture, they will interact with me, and they will interact with this whole machine.
100xEngineers: Can you think of this…
100xEngineers: No, I don't want to, like, just throw jargons here. So the rule for this first principle discussion is, like, no jargons. Like, I'm sure, like, throughout everything which I'm writing, I'm not using any jargon. I could use, like, a number of jargons, and I know, like, a lot of them, but the expectation from you as well is not to put, like, anything which…
100xEngineers: I would say, like, you… you cannot, like, explain this to, like, a 7-year-old or 10-year-old.
100xEngineers: Explain like a 5-year-old. Use that analogy, because it'll help you to also simplify things in your own head.
100xEngineers: My question here, again, just to… Revise.
100xEngineers: We assume that everybody can interact with this machine with ZoomChat, whatever I had.
100xEngineers: But what if, like, somebody's watching as a pre-recorded lecture, because then the chat is not available to them?
100xEngineers: What is the first thing we need here? Like, let's solve this problem. We solve the communication problem by language. Let's solve this problem of…
100xEngineers: Reaching out to this machine. I would say, like, how can we reach out to this machine?
100xEngineers: how to… Reach out to this machine slash service.
100xEngineers: Via website?
100xEngineers: You are?
100xEngineers: Yeah?
100xEngineers: So, we need, we need, something for that, like, some people who are saying website.
100xEngineers: Or maybe some, some, some sort of, like, Address we need, right?
100xEngineers: What do we call that address? If I need to, like, open a website.
100xEngineers: Or even if I need to go to a place, right? Let's say this machine is sitting somewhere in Bangalore, right? So I need…
100xEngineers: Website… location.
100xEngineers: or slash location, like, website if this is on the internet, location if it is a physical machine, and it can be accessed only by a physical. So I need some type of location.
100xEngineers: Yes, the IP address… And,
100xEngineers: Most people don't understand IP address and don't remember IP address, so for that, we have URLs.
100xEngineers: This is the location of the machines on the internet.
100xEngineers: For the physical ones, we have the address. Like, you can say the post address.
100xEngineers: Postal address.
100xEngineers: I would have my postal address where the machine is sitting. Maybe it's my office, like Bangalore, Hebwal, Belgi Road,
100xEngineers: with a PIN code of, like, 560092. So I'll, like, have my whole,
100xEngineers: postal address, which is here. If this is…
100xEngineers: machine which is only accessible from a physical location. If it is accessible from a, like, an internet, then the location is a URL. So I can use this URL, and this becomes the… the primary way for me to, like, access this machine when I can't have the live access to this via Zoom chat.
100xEngineers: And this is, to be honest, like, how somebody has thought about all of these problems in 1950s and 1940s, when we were building computers, and we were building the network of computers. So, in this case, I was like, I'll do the URL, which is the location.
100xEngineers: Based on our discussion, we have identified we need these three things.
100xEngineers: We definitely need a location, right? This is the primary interface, or you can even say, like, location, where we can reach out to this machine. Could be via a live… if somebody's attending live, then Zoom chat. If they're not attending live, they want to reach out to this machine, then via URL, if it is on web, if it is on a physical location, maybe an address.
100xEngineers: Then we need a language.
100xEngineers: A common language? Actually, this needs to be a common language.
100xEngineers: Because we are… we are communicating between two different parties, right? So it needs to be a common language.
100xEngineers: In this case, it's English, and then the rules. Format of the input, format of the output.
100xEngineers: What you guys have just… described. This is the… Protocol of how you Communicate.
100xEngineers: With the machine that is sitting on internet, maybe somewhere else, and which
100xEngineers: Which can give you some kind of answers. And if you understand all of these things, this is what goes into building protocols. Set of rules, like, what we said, like, we need some set of rules here.
100xEngineers: So, these are the set of rules, or I would say the protocol, which is, like, a more military word, which is taken from, like, military, because internet, if you go to the history of internet, it was initially designed for the ARPANET, which was, like, a military project, and a lot of the keywords actually, like, came from those.
100xEngineers: But this is a whole protocol, right? And what we have designed, this is the same protocol somebody has designed, like, hundreds years ago, to decide how they can communicate with different machines. And this is important not only for humans, but with other machines as well. As I said, like, if I am building a weather machine, and I need to talk to a Google machine.
100xEngineers: If this set of rules are clear across everybody, everybody understands that A we need a location, then we need a common language, then we need some set of rules which defines the input and output, and if we have all of these things, then we can talk to
100xEngineers: different machines which are on the network. So if this is a weather…
100xEngineers: machine, and then this machine wants to talk to… actually, let me do this.
100xEngineers: Let's say this is a weather machine, and this machine wants to talk to the machine of Google, because somebody said that you should check Google for your weather reports. And, so first thing, in order for us to establish it, what is the first thing we need?
100xEngineers: And let's do a quick… API design.
100xEngineers: Okay, this is what it looks like.
100xEngineers: if I want to, like, tell my weather machine, NRA machine, that you need to reach out to Google, what is the first thing we need?
100xEngineers: And let's define things very clearly.
100xEngineers: The URL, the API URL, right? API URL.
100xEngineers: We definitely need API, but I'll… I'll keep the URL as of now, but…
100xEngineers: Some sort of location on the internet, because I know Google lives on the internet.
100xEngineers: How can I find this? I can go to Google.
100xEngineers: And, this is the address of Google, right? And if I can inspect… now, this is not necessary, but I'm just still telling you, and if I…
100xEngineers: Maybe just do a refresh.
100xEngineers: And I can see there are, like, multiple…
100xEngineers: Clearly, let me do this.
100xEngineers: Yeah, so this is the first request which we made.
100xEngineers: If you can see, this is to the google.com. This is the request URL.
100xEngineers: This is the request URL.
100xEngineers: Let me come back to my part here. This is the first thing which every browser does. It needs to understand what is the URL, and it makes a request to this URL.
100xEngineers: So, step number one, what we described right now.
100xEngineers: Now, the second step is… Or the second step.
100xEngineers: My weather machine needs to talk to Google.
100xEngineers: a Google service.
100xEngineers: We just got the Google request URL.
100xEngineers: What's the second step here?
100xEngineers: Based on this.
100xEngineers: Don't think about, like, your previous information. Just for… for a moment, forget about everything what you have learned previously.
100xEngineers: Just think that you are a 5-year-old person who is just, like, watching this.
100xEngineers: Or maybe, like, a 10-year-old, slightly older.
100xEngineers: Based on everything what we discussed, we have the request URL. The second thing, yes, Sagar, awesome, and Yash, we need to establish a common language, because without that, how will I interact? How will my weather service will know that… how to speak to Google.com?
100xEngineers: Right? We need to establish a language, just like what we decided with the protocol that we designed right now.
100xEngineers: Now, this is an important question. How many of you Can guess this.
100xEngineers: there's a slight bias towards it, all the coders in the house, they can guess it, but I want them to actually, like, stay silent. If you are somebody who is a developer who has written code previously about, like, building APIs, don't answer this question right now. I want to just, like, see people who have not written code.
100xEngineers: Can they guess it?
100xEngineers: what is the language we can use, and what is the language which you think is the ideal language for my weather machine to talk to Google?
100xEngineers: Okay, I'll read out a few answers.
100xEngineers: Ram said, Jason, in Otini said, HTTP. HTTP is a protocol in Otini.
100xEngineers: It's not, the language. So, HTTP is like a protocol just like this. It's a set of rules.
100xEngineers: Not a language. Java is a language.
100xEngineers: So it's not… NAC.
100xEngineers: said Java, and
100xEngineers: Recursion response body, it's… it's a format, hunch, it's not a language. Python is a language, yes.
100xEngineers: And, Nick said Python, Methly said maths. Okay, wow. So I have a couple of candidates with me. Let's see, like, let's test all of these things right now.
100xEngineers: So we have Mads from Metly.
100xEngineers: We have… Python from beneath.
100xEngineers: And we have Java from Jaskirith.
100xEngineers: I'm just, like, actually making up all of these things. I'm just trying to find the same name, same initials. But, we have some of the candidates right now, and we have Vishteml also, by the way. Interesting.
100xEngineers: We have something called JSON.
100xEngineers: REST is not a language, Aniroth. REST is another protocol.
100xEngineers: Okay, I'll stop here, because I think there's, like, multiple other options which are coming in here, but…
100xEngineers: I'll stop because I have to also give you the right answer. You can also go Node.js, JavaScript.
100xEngineers: Now, math is a very interesting answer, by the way. First of all, kudos to Methli, right?
100xEngineers: Because maths is an answer, and
100xEngineers: In a way, like, I can actually describe it. Like, I can tell my weather application that only use mathematics. The problem with mathematics is that you have to fall back to the binary, because this is what machines will understand. So you have to write some sort of binary version, because Google servers can understand that. It is possible.
100xEngineers: So yes, math could become a candidate for a common language, because every machine in the world understands mathematics, understands binary. Binary is the type of language using the numbers, so we can actually have a communication. The only problem here is, who is designing this communication?
100xEngineers: This is mostly a developer, a human being, because the builder of a weather API, as well as builder and maintainer of the google.com, as a company, they are not machines, they are human beings.
100xEngineers: As of now, machines have not replaced everybody yet, so still, like, people maintain these softwares and do all of these things.
100xEngineers: The problem is, it's efficient, is the most efficient… maths is the most efficient language between two machines, but it is the most inefficient language for a human being to understand and write code.
100xEngineers: I have written my first program in binary when I was in class 12, and it took me…
100xEngineers: some… 100 lines to just add 2 numbers.
100xEngineers: We're just trying to, like, find the right operator, right operand, and then this entire thing translated into assembly language, which is the slightly, again, a lower-level language, but it has, like, English keywords associated with each and every binary, so this is…
100xEngineers: slightly easier version of it, we can say that, and a lot of the systems are built on assembly right now. The problem with mathematics is
100xEngineers: It's difficult for the human being who is building these systems and these APIs, and hence, like, it's gonna be very difficult for that communication part. But I think your guess was very smart, because machines can understand maths, it's fun. I won't reject it because humans can't understand it.
100xEngineers: Second thing is Python. So we had Python from Shefali, right? Let's assess if Python can become a common language for everything. Now, in order for me to make sure whether my application understands Python or the other application which I'm building.
100xEngineers: I need to know Python as a developer, so I have to find people who know Python, who can maintain it.
100xEngineers: And, I can obviously, like, hire these people, or maybe learn Python myself, and build all of these things. That is part one of building my machine. Now, second thing is.
100xEngineers: I also need to make sure that Google understand Python.
100xEngineers: Because if I go to google.com right now, I… don't…
100xEngineers: have any clarity that what Google's server is doing, because that is a part which is not accessible to me. I can only see the beautiful website which is present there, but nobody knows
100xEngineers: Unless until you have written the, the architecture, and there are, like, ways to, like, figure it out, but as of now, I won't go into the, like, the nitty of this, but it's difficult to identify, as I, as I said.
100xEngineers: whether Google used Python or not.
100xEngineers: Right, the only way to test is we send everything in Python.
100xEngineers: And we can actually do that, like, whatever Google's URL is, you can write a Python program, and you can send it to the Google. I'll show you, like, an exercise, and you can… hopefully you'll do that by end of this lecture.
100xEngineers: But I've tried, and it failed.
100xEngineers: If I send Python code, exact Python code, nothing else, to this URL,
100xEngineers: I've tried it, personally. It will fail. And it will not fail because Python is the wrong language, or it's something which Google doesn't understand. Definitely, somebody who's working at Google might know Python. But nobody knows that system that you have built, the machine that
100xEngineers: the same machine which is getting used to render this page, or deliver this page on your web browser right now, is the machine that understands Python.
100xEngineers: Because that is also a very important part, right? And maybe, like, someone else has built
100xEngineers: something with Python using Google, but this is not a common language.
100xEngineers: That is the premise here.
100xEngineers: Because… Python is a language which can help you to build, like, backend services, so does Java.
100xEngineers: In the same way, like, how you can build Python apps, you can build Java apps.
100xEngineers: You can also build apps with HTML, you can also build apps with C++, and all of these languages. Node.js as well.
100xEngineers: Just one clarification here,
100xEngineers: HTML is not a programming language. It's a markup language, which means that you can set the structure of what is the data you want to present on a page.
100xEngineers: Hence, like, this is not the same thing, in the sense that you can't build a backend server with an HTML. That is not possible. So, apart from HTML, all of these languages can be used to build a backend, and they can build the exact same thing. It's just the implementation gonna be different. Which means it's always gonna be a guess for me that
100xEngineers: will this system understand Java, Python, C++, Node.js, and other things or not? And I can try multiple times, but…
100xEngineers: Because there is no universal programming language as of now. However, people do have this priority that, okay, this language is popular, this is not popular.
100xEngineers: But we don't have a universal language as of now.
100xEngineers: in the programming world, which every single person used in their life to build all the applications, right? Myself, I have used, like, multiple programming languages to build multiple applications. So if we have multiple apps, let's say the Google's app is built using Java, and now
100xEngineers: Shefali is sending the information with Python. This will not work.
100xEngineers: Right? So…
100xEngineers: I can't use Python. For same reason, I can't use Java. And HTML, because it's not a programming language, so it's not in the picture. C++ is great, but same reason. I don't know whether Google understands C++ right now, or the machine that Google is using to render my page understands C++ as of now.
100xEngineers: And I've tried, by the way, all of this.
100xEngineers: Same goes with JavaScript and Node.js, because I don't know exactly if they understand this language.
100xEngineers: what we have remaining here is Jason, and Jason, just to give you
100xEngineers: One more bit about JSON. JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation. It's not a language, it's…
100xEngineers: A text-based format that's used to store and transport data.
100xEngineers: So, the thing which somebody has mentioned in the chat.
100xEngineers: And I'll basically keep it here.
100xEngineers: On the whiteboard.
100xEngineers: This is what JSON stands for, JavaScript Object Notation. It's not a language, it's a lightweight text-based format used to store and transport data. Very similar to how we have markdown files.
100xEngineers: We have text files, we have docs file. If you use something like this, I download this file. I can download it in docs file, in PDF, different formats are there. In the same way, you can also
100xEngineers: convert everything in the JSON format. Like, if I have to do this right now, I can actually show you,
100xEngineers: Quickly, maybe, let's say… I'll ask.
100xEngineers: convert this into JSON.
100xEngineers: So this is the discovery document of RF, and I'll do the instant for this right now. Give me the instant answer, hopefully.
100xEngineers: So it's gonna take all the text document, and it's gonna translate everything to JSON. This is how the JSON looks like.
100xEngineers: Some of you might have seen this, some of you might not have seen this. This looks slightly cryptic to a few people, but this is the format.
100xEngineers: Just like a text is a format, PDF is a format, Markdown is a format.
100xEngineers: JSON is a format which we use,
100xEngineers: like, it was initially started with JavaScript only, because that's where the name came in, but we were beside using this format in a lot of other languages as well.
100xEngineers: The reason why I gave you this history is because this is actually, like, a good candidate.
100xEngineers: And the reason why it's a good candidate is because it's…
100xEngineers: As I said, not a language, it's a format.
100xEngineers: If we can… if we can agree that whatever language you're choosing, irrespective if it is Python, Java, C++, or maybe somebody has built this thing with N10, or somebody wipe-coded the Google.com with Lovable.
100xEngineers: Which, in itself, uses JavaScript, by the way, and JS and Node.js as a whole system, so…
100xEngineers: No matter whatever The… the engine is on the other machine.
100xEngineers: if we can decide the format, right, like a format which is universally acceptable, and this is where the JSON comes in, because JSON is the only format
100xEngineers: which is universally acceptable in the programming industry. If you use Java, if you use C++, if you use Node.js, if you use Python.
100xEngineers: Lavable, N8, and JS, any language in the world. They have
100xEngineers: a way to read and write JSON.
100xEngineers: Because it's a format. And this format became accessible and more universal, because everything on internet uses JavaScript as a client site, and
100xEngineers: everybody needs to understand what this format is, because everything was written in this format in the early days of the internet. And because it was like that, it became, like, a whole norm.
100xEngineers: So, very good answer, whoever said this. Very good candidate, and it can become a language, because
100xEngineers: as I said, it is not as complicated
100xEngineers: As compared to all other things, right? So, literally, like, anyone can write this. If you have
100xEngineers: a piece of text. This works like this. It starts with a curly brace and ends with that. So wherever this curly brace is ending, it means this is where the file is ending.
100xEngineers: And, it works with key and values. So this is a key, which is the program name. This is the value.
100xEngineers: And then you can have nested elements, which is this observation, and this could be another JSON,
100xEngineers: Which is gonna be, again, key, and the value.
100xEngineers: The reason why I'm spending time here is because this is gonna be the rest of your
100xEngineers: API response, API request, everything what you will see on the internet today.
100xEngineers: They have established a common language.
100xEngineers: And they have not established a common language like Java, C++, or Node.js, they have established a common language on JSON. This is primarily on web APIs.
100xEngineers: Anything which is on web?
100xEngineers: If I go to Google right now again… just to…
100xEngineers: prove this part, which I'm trying to explain, and I've opened the network tab.
100xEngineers: Let me see this create part, or let's say, get async data, a lot of things, by the way.
100xEngineers: Let me send something, if I can directly get the query which I'm sending.
100xEngineers: Okay.
100xEngineers: So we have this, so… Query little…
100xEngineers: And this is what the response came back. This entire response, as you can see, it's also in a… actually, this one. Like, all of these responses are really following similar format, right? Like, key-value pair, key-value pair. This is, like, the set of things.
100xEngineers: This is another one, which is the chunk.
100xEngineers: If I use the example of ChatGPT, maybe that would be, like, easier.
100xEngineers: Because a lot of things are going on Google's server right now, I'm assuming.
100xEngineers: Let's keep this as a clean example.
100xEngineers: network tab, and I'll try to first send one message. So I'll try to, like, see if I can find this message in the network tab, and inspect right now, live, how this thing works.
100xEngineers: Oh, wait, I need to connect my charger.
100xEngineers: Okay, so I can see the conversation here.
100xEngineers: And you can also see something. This is chatgb.com slash backend API.
100xEngineers: Which is the request URL.
100xEngineers: And then we get some response, right? This response is how it looks like.
100xEngineers: It has a lot of things, it has the data.
100xEngineers: I help you with. So, as you can see, it's sending a lot of information here, but using the same format, right, a key-value pair and the curly braces. So, it…
100xEngineers: It helps us to…
100xEngineers: like, validate everything what we are learning, and you can find all of this information here as well, that…
100xEngineers: Every API.
100xEngineers: in the backend, it uses the same principles and the same protocols. Coming back to the whole thing, I know this might be intimidating for some people, what we are doing, but…
100xEngineers: This is what…
100xEngineers: looks like to design a protocol, right? And what we have done right now in the last 30 minutes, not sure how many of you realize.
100xEngineers: is what exactly, 50 to 60 years ago, somebody…
100xEngineers: in the rooms of CERN, and people who are, like, building HTTP, maybe Tim Berners-Lee and his team, might have done the same exercise. So we have, like.
100xEngineers: derived all those things, and how can a machine communicate with another machine on the internet? It needs a request URL, it needs to establish a common language, and finally, it needs to establish the
100xEngineers: the rules for input, output, and what is going to be the format for this. Now, because we have already established the JSON as a common language.
100xEngineers: It's gonna be much easier for us to define the rules and the input, and just to come back here…
100xEngineers: if I talk about the conversation itself, I can see the… the payload. This is where the messages comes in, and if you can see, this… this is specifically the content, the type, text, the part, hey, this is the word I have sent on my…
100xEngineers: machine.
100xEngineers: which goes, and my front-end system package everything with, like, a lot of extra information, like the conversation mode, the client contextual information, there's a lot of other things which my browser is doing behind the scenes, which I have no idea. But what I can see and what I can validate from this entire thing, this inspection, is that
100xEngineers: This is the part which I have typed here, and it's getting wrapped
100xEngineers: Into some sort of a similar language that we have seen here, like, with the key and values and some curly braces and square braces.
100xEngineers: And, it packages this information, sends it to a URL. This is the location, which is a ChatGPT backend, slash conversation. And once it sends all this information.
100xEngineers: This becomes the input format.
100xEngineers: this becomes the input format, where whenever you want to talk to GPT-5.5, First, we identify the location.
100xEngineers: We identify the common language, which is right now using JSON, and then we identify the common format. This is the format. And once we have format, we send this data in this format, and we expect the output, and output gets in this format, which is, like, a lot of text in the same JSON part.
100xEngineers: Now… Once you know this, If I now type another message.
100xEngineers: It's gonna follow the exact same path.
100xEngineers: Because there were multiple requests which were getting done from my end.
100xEngineers: I think my system was lagging. I hope now you can see it. Surprisingly, this is also, what…
100xEngineers: ChatGPT's new feature is, and I'll talk more about it in the future lectures, this is the generative UI part of it, but…
100xEngineers: What I can tell you again is that every single time when I want to have a conversation and I send a message, you can find a pattern, you can do it by yourself, and you can find this in your network tab. If somebody wants to follow this along. You need to be on a Chrome, just to…
100xEngineers: Do the same part, where…
100xEngineers: Click on the right click, inspect, go to the network tab, and make sure you select the fetch slash etc, so it will only show you the request. And whenever you send a message, now, just try to observe what is happening in this, thing.
100xEngineers: Again, for some reason, the chat GPT is still loading. It's, like, taking too much time.
100xEngineers: But whenever you send something here.
100xEngineers: you'll see this calling the same API in the same exact format. So what we have decoded or reverse engineered from this entire experiment, which is a slightly shaky experiment because of the network I had, sorry.
100xEngineers: But we found a common language that ChatGPT uses, you can use it for Google as well, and it uses a specific input format. You saw that the Model 5.5, the conversation, the user profile, all of those things are part of the input format that it accepts. And then it does some processing, definitely, in the backend.
100xEngineers: and then gives the output in the JSON format in the same… same part.
100xEngineers: By having this, we understand something very, very, I would say, core of
100xEngineers: system design, is that how these two different machines can communicate, because now I can use the same information, I can build my own software, or maybe I can build an agent, and I can give this information to an agent, and an agent can use the same request URL, as long as it knows that where the data goes, what is the common language, what are the rules, what is the format of input and output, it can talk to this
100xEngineers: API. And because API is a standard, everything on the internet follows this standard.
100xEngineers: And that is what I was telling you, like, this is the protocol which everybody follows. And because this is a protocol which everybody followed.
100xEngineers: And it initially started with the internet, which…
100xEngineers: Which had, like, a lot of text and the hypertext.
100xEngineers: That's what we call hypertext.
100xEngineers: transfer… Protocol.
100xEngineers: If you have heard this term before.
100xEngineers: This is what it means, and this is what it does. Some people said HTTP. This is what HTTP stands for, a hypertext Transfer Protocol. Hypertext is a text which is clickable. Anything which you see on the… your web, whatever is clickable, this is a hypertext.
100xEngineers: Back in the day, when internet was very new, the only thing which it had is pages, and then links to other pages. So, the network was…
100xEngineers: worldwide web of this internet, and the way how…
100xEngineers: they established all these communications. They call this Hypertext Transfer Protocol, which governs each and everything on the internet.
100xEngineers: No.
100xEngineers: the information which I shared with all of you is… is something which…
100xEngineers: hopefully gonna help you to look at all the internet services and the websites slightly differently. Maybe from next time onwards, you can start inspecting and try to find out the URL, and this is gonna be common across, like, most of the languages. There might be some cases where you'll find something different, but majority of the part
100xEngineers: Of the internet which we use today.
100xEngineers: they have established JSON as a common language, and then you have, like, some formats. This is gonna be different for each and every input, right? The way how Anthropic expects the input is different from how OpenAI expects the input, or how, like, other API expects the input, because this is very subjective to the machine itself.
100xEngineers: And this is also, like, because somebody has thought of the same way, right? We have to design a system, and this design… this system needs to take the input and output. That's why it connects back to our…
100xEngineers: the first principle of building all of this. So this is what…
100xEngineers: the core, I would say, like, I have to share everything compressed in this format.
100xEngineers: Now, why this is useful? Now, some of you might be scratching your head, and some of you might be wondering, some of you… I'm definitely sure that, some of you are zoned out right now, because I've been, like.
100xEngineers: Giving a monologue, and sharing a lot of things. Now, to bring back all the zoned-out people, I have an exercise, which will hopefully
100xEngineers: Make everything what we discussed on the whiteboard
100xEngineers: much more practical, and for this exercise, I'll share this link. I…
100xEngineers: I actually need my team. If Homka, you are here, can you send this link on the…
100xEngineers: Discord, as well as on the chat.
100xEngineers: We have uploaded this on the LMS.
100xEngineers: Yeah, this is the file.
100xEngineers: So, the resources section… If you're not able to open LMS, you can find it from the
100xEngineers: Discord resource section. Apart from that, we have also mentioned it on the LMS, so you can… you can go to LMS and you can find this. But for now, I want all of you to
100xEngineers: download this file. This is an HTML file.
100xEngineers: Which means it's a web page. You can download this webpage, and you can open it in your browser.
100xEngineers: I'll also show you how to download this.
100xEngineers: You can click on this, you can download, and you can click on this, it'll open a frame like this on your browser.
100xEngineers: What I want you to do in the next, 5 to 10 minutes.
100xEngineers: I'll walk you through the exercise.
100xEngineers: We'll do it one by one. There are 5 exercises.
100xEngineers: Actually, the first one is, like, pretty straightforward. It starts from exactly where we did, and this is also, like, serves as a recap of everything what I have done, but in a much more interactive manner.
100xEngineers: Everybody got this file? Let's do a quick check on hand raise. If you have installed this file on your machine, and if you have opened this on your browser.
100xEngineers: Just raise your hand.
100xEngineers: Raise your hand if you have got this file.
100xEngineers: If not, go to Discord, you can download it from the resource channel.
100xEngineers: You can also find it on the LMS.
100xEngineers: This is a screen you should… you should be able to see.
100xEngineers: Just go to Discord, download this file, open this file on your browser, that's all.
100xEngineers: Awesome, we have…
100xEngineers: Finished it.
100xEngineers: Cool. People who are catching up, you can continue, it won't take, like, too much time, but I'll give you the gist of exercise one by one. The first exercise is exactly the same interface which all of you have built. This is where we started the conversation today.
100xEngineers: We all learned in the previous lecture about user interfaces, what kind of user interfaces are there, and how to basically build one.
100xEngineers: On a… on a very, like, simple level.
100xEngineers: This is the interface which I built with the code track.
100xEngineers: it takes the input, gives some output back. Right now, if you click on Submit, this will give you the exact data back, and this is exactly what we built. The EcoBot, if some of you remember from the Codra exercise. But, this entire thing was just to understand whether we can build an interface, and this is, like, the easiest way to do it.
100xEngineers: Once you have established this is the interface, the interface is important here, because you need to know, as I said, like, where we are putting the input, where we are getting the output. This is the box for the input and output, and this is the button you click. When you click it, it will take this input.
100xEngineers: it will start the processing, if I have to connect it back with my diagram. So, right now, we have the front-end part of it only. It'll take some input, process it, and then give the output back.
100xEngineers: So this is what it is doing right now, but because it doesn't have any backend, doesn't have any other system, so it's just repeating what it says. This is where we started the lecture today. The next exercise…
100xEngineers: is… what I was asking you guys as an experiment, right, where I asked you, If I'm a machine.
100xEngineers: How can we communicate with each other? And how can you get the data from me?
100xEngineers: This is the bridge. This is the… this is where the second interface comes in, which is API. That stands for Application Programming Interface. As we understand, UI is a communication layer between a human being and the system. That's where the UI… this is what we built.
100xEngineers: But the second thing which we need in order for us to process the information is the second interface, the API, which will send the data and do some processing on some backend somewhere, and then give the data back.
100xEngineers: The thing which I've mentioned here to everybody, every API call on the Earth, no matter who built it, is just four things. We can compress it down to these four principles.
100xEngineers: where the endpoint is, which means I was trying to understand this in… in the exercise, like…
100xEngineers: where are you gonna reach out to me? Like, this is also part of the first… Rule.
100xEngineers: Where this machine is located, where can I find the address of this machine?
100xEngineers: After this.
100xEngineers: the action. Once you know the endpoint, which means the address of that machine, that service, usually it's going to be a URL, just like what we see in ChatGPT URL backend, the Google URL. After that, we need to understand the action, right? And this is about, like, what
100xEngineers: you want.
100xEngineers: Yeah, understanding where this machine sits, but what exactly you want this machine to do. Do you want this machine to check the weather, Google, the Bangalore weather, or summarize it, and be very concise? In order for us to describe what we want, we need a common language.
100xEngineers: The action here is the method.
100xEngineers: Now, this…
100xEngineers: is a part which is very interesting for machines, because if you talk to human beings, you need to describe everything in a way that the other person can understand. But because machines are much more deterministic, humans have
100xEngineers: created a set of methods, and I list down all these methods for all of you. Actually, I have, I think, maybe a slide for this, so I'll…
100xEngineers: Yeah, these are the methods.
100xEngineers: Get, post, put, patch, and delete.
100xEngineers: Now, GET is a method, which is a short form for give me weather.
100xEngineers: It means that I want to read some information which is there on the server, or there on the backend.
100xEngineers: post… is a short form for creating and sending something. Like, here's a workflow, create a diagnosis.
100xEngineers: Here is the… weather details, get a report out of it. Here is my message, generate.
100xEngineers: answer generate something. So, whenever you're trying to create something from that machine, from the service, we use post as a method.
100xEngineers: Port and patch are something which we use to update that
100xEngineers: things which already exist. Let's say if I have…
100xEngineers: created a workflow already, I want to update that workflow. I'll use put. The difference between put and patch is very, like, subtle.
100xEngineers: put actually creates, if I'm not wrong, just to be precise.
100xEngineers: put replaces the entire resource, where patch applies a partial modification.
100xEngineers: I never use patch, to be honest. I mostly use put most of the time, because one of my key roles to design software is immutability, which means that I don't want to make any part of my software which has, like, some kind of history, some kind of trauma.
100xEngineers: Because I have seen that it doesn't work really well with human beings. So everything which I do, like, if I'm building a software, I try to, like… if I want to update a part, I will try to replace what it was there, and then add a new part to it.
100xEngineers: We definitely can, like, don't need to, like, use this as a…
100xEngineers: hard recommendation, but, you know, like, how I use it. These are two methods, put and patch, both of them does the update, but the way they do it is differently. So, put replaces, as I said, the entire resource. For example, if you have built a workflow, what it does, and you want to, let's say, make a change, let's say this workflow, which you have built.
100xEngineers: This is the entire file, and you want to change the name of this file. There are two ways to do that. One is, I will go and edit this file and only change this part. That is patch. One where I delete everything, and I rewrite the whole thing, but I will just make this part with an updated change. That is put,
100xEngineers: And the last one is a delete. So the other four parts, are the four methods, and you can compress down every single API on the Earth, every single way how you can communicate what action you want to do.
100xEngineers: what you want this machine to take. Like, if you want to get… let's do a quick exercise. If I want…
100xEngineers: And let me post, get… host.
100xEngineers: Put and delete.
100xEngineers: So… This also stands for a very common notion, which is called CRUD.
100xEngineers: This is… create…
100xEngineers: Indeed.
100xEngineers: Update and delete.
100xEngineers: If you have heard these terminologies before.
100xEngineers: This is where, like, it actually becomes useful.
100xEngineers: I'll keep the… Post part first.
100xEngineers: So it matches with the… credit operations.
100xEngineers: This is how… We can compress down everything, like, this is the ultimate compression of…
100xEngineers: What action we want other machines to do.
100xEngineers: So… If I give you this right now…
100xEngineers: Now I'll do an exercise, let's do a quick exercise to understand whether you Grasp the concepts or not.
100xEngineers: let's say I am right now fetching the weather, and my query looks like this, which is…
100xEngineers: Where's that query? This is the query.
100xEngineers: A query is like this.
100xEngineers: And, for me, I first need to put the Bangalore city as the name.
100xEngineers: But this is the intent which I want.
100xEngineers: Give me your weather details for the 1st June of Bangalore City, India PIN code F560006.
100xEngineers: What is the method I should use?
100xEngineers: Actually, this is not the… I'll use this one like that.
100xEngineers: This is your user. Or it could be an app, like your app.
100xEngineers: Yes… People who said GET, you were right, people who said post.
100xEngineers: Wrong answer, because post, as I just mentioned, is used to create something. Are we creating something?
100xEngineers: When we are asking for the weather details.
100xEngineers: Go back to the same example, here.
100xEngineers: get means read and fetch, give me the weather data. POST means send or create something.
100xEngineers: Are we sending, actually, sending is, like, slightly ambiguous, but create is the keyword you need to always think about. Associate post with creation. Like, are we creating something? Are we generating something on the server itself?
100xEngineers: If not, then…
100xEngineers: it's always gonna be get, like, when we want to fetch the information, right? Now, let me change the query.
100xEngineers: This is becoming slightly crowded, so I'll move a few things here.
100xEngineers: Let me ask you the second part.
100xEngineers: This is the query. Somebody wants to do this.
100xEngineers: They want to update the weather. Maybe they have logged in as an admin. They saw that right now, the weather on this page is showing 25 degree, but the actual weather right now, it's different. So what I want is, I want to change this weather detail.
100xEngineers: And, this is a query which I've written, update the weather for Bangalore City.
100xEngineers: to 24 degrees Celsius. What is the method? Just method. Out of all of this, post, get, put, delete, should I use…
100xEngineers: put… Yes.
100xEngineers: Awesome.
100xEngineers: Now there's a slightly different question.
100xEngineers: I'll go back to my ChatGPT example.
100xEngineers: If we are sending this…
100xEngineers: If you have opened ChatGPT, and now we are asking what is the weather in Bangalore?
100xEngineers: If you're asking what is weather in Bangalore, and let me open this right now in front of you, so you will get this…
100xEngineers: What's the weather?
100xEngineers: What is the method of request which we need here?
100xEngineers: The same method, which… ChatGPT use.
100xEngineers: Out of all of this… Post, get, put, delete.
100xEngineers: when I write something to ChatGPT as a prompt.
100xEngineers: Think about this, because this is a tricky question.
100xEngineers: Take a step back. People who are saying get.
100xEngineers: First of all, put is… put is completely wrong. So people who are at put and delete, they're… this is completely wrong. We're not updating anything. So definitely, it has to be between get and post, that is the right answer. Something between GET and POST.
100xEngineers: Now, let's examine whether GET is the right answer.
100xEngineers: Now, GET is actually to read information.
100xEngineers: And when we use the same example in the first time, I asked the same question that gave me a weather forecast, but I asked this question to a weather service.
100xEngineers: And here, this is a GET request because the data is already lying in the server, and it just needs to fetch that information and show me. So I am reading that information which is already there.
100xEngineers: Look at ChatGPT.
100xEngineers: One principle which I shared with all of you is that every single thing that ChatGPT gives me as an output, it generates that output.
100xEngineers: Large language models are generative AI.
100xEngineers: Very important word. The GPT stands for Generative Pre-Trained Transformer.
100xEngineers: So it's generating each and every token.
100xEngineers: It's not reading it from a database which is storing this information. It might make a request to another database, it can make a tool call, but even to make that tool call, it has to generate the code. It has to generate everything. So the way how LLM works in this chat GPT works is generating everything. Because it is generating everything.
100xEngineers: And we know for creation and generation, we use the post method. The answer is POST, and you can verify this right now. The beauty of learning from POST principles is that everything around you works on these principles, and you can verify this. If I have to…
100xEngineers: Write one more time.
100xEngineers: This is a conversation, and can you see the post method here?
100xEngineers: This is the proof.
100xEngineers: That whatever we discuss, whatever we learn, this is the exact way how ChatGPT has built its API. This is how people think, right? And if you can get the same mental model which I was trying to teach today, like.
100xEngineers: This is what's gonna help you to not only just build API, but also learn and read APIs on the internet. And once you know this, you can connect your app with anything.
100xEngineers: So, I hope you got the gist, because it's important. And now you can do this exercise every time you use a new application. Open that application, try to guess that for each and every action, what the method should look like for this API.
100xEngineers: And sometimes it would be easy, sometimes it would be difficult, but as I said, like, if you use the first principles and reasoning from that, you should be able to do
100xEngineers: like, some… some reasoning for this. And if you want to confirm, you can just always open the network tab and check the request method. You can always find it.
100xEngineers: There will be slight variation for some companies, because, as I said, not every company might use the best practices. There are people in some companies who might think that this is a GET request, and they can do that. Not the best practice, and they eventually figure out it.
100xEngineers: So I'll not use it as a source of truth on the internet, but all the top labs and the top companies, they have, like, a well, I would say, predefined methods which they use, and they mostly, like, follow the same journey, and this is a best practice which we have. So…
100xEngineers: Okay, this is the second exercise which we were doing here.
100xEngineers: So we got… Now, where the endpoint was, This is the rules.
100xEngineers: part.
100xEngineers: Then we establish the language, and then we establish the methods, the action, what it does, so get, read, post, delete. And then we also need to know that what is the data that request body hand over. This is the input part, which is the input, the format of input.
100xEngineers: what it sends, and what it receives back as a response. This is the output.
100xEngineers: And once you know these four things, which is exactly what we derived from first principles today itself, like, I don't know, like, how many of you, again, take this
100xEngineers: part, but I can tell you that 90% of the engineers, engineers who are writing code in production, they themselves would understand how to derive these things, why we have a request URL, why we have a method, and why we should use post method to, like, get and generate information, why we need to have a format of the input, and why the format looks like this. Because this is something which
100xEngineers: Which takes a lot of free time and overthinking, which I don't think a lot of people have.
100xEngineers: And that's the only power which I think I have right now, like…
100xEngineers: A lot of free time and overthinking. But coming back to it, then…
100xEngineers: This… this is what we were discussing here. If you have, like, these four things, you can, like, start
100xEngineers: The next exercise, this is where we actually connect it. So all of you, I want you to go to the exercise number 3.
100xEngineers: We're gonna write our first API.
100xEngineers: And I will introduce you to…
100xEngineers: a new tool, but before using that, I'll also open this API
100xEngineers: As a website, and I'll share it with all of you. This is the website called httpbin.org.
100xEngineers: It's a simple HTTP request-response service.
100xEngineers: And it is often used to teach people about, like, APIs. If you are somebody who wants to go do a rabbit hole tonight, deep down, you can continue with this website.
100xEngineers: what I will do right now is that I'll take this exact URL,
100xEngineers: which is written here, and I'll write some text Hello.
100xEngineers: Actually, hello, world, because this is the convention link in the programming.
100xEngineers: And if I write this text, and I'll send this text in the chat right now, to everybody.
100xEngineers: Just open this URL on your browser.
100xEngineers: And you should be able to see something like this. If you can, let me know in the chat.
100xEngineers: If you saw the same URL.
100xEngineers: How many of you saw this URL?
100xEngineers: Awesome.
100xEngineers: Congratulations to all of you, you have made your first successful API call.
100xEngineers: people who have got this same URL and the same response, you have made your first successful call, so congratulations, you can mark this lecture successful, and you can go home right now.
100xEngineers: No, actually, I'm not telling you to go home. That was just a joke. But this is the first part of calling API. There's one more last exercise I have for you guys. I'll extend this lecture to 10 more minutes.
100xEngineers: But I'll finish this part.
100xEngineers: Well, good job, man. Good job, the men and women and everyone in the room who have made the first API call. Now, what I want all of you to do as an exercise is
100xEngineers: Make changes to this right now.
100xEngineers: I have already connected this endpoint with the interface.
100xEngineers: So what you need to do is you need to make changes to this URL.
100xEngineers: So that you can output the saved text, but not via an API.
100xEngineers: what this API does, it just echoes everything, as you already saw. If you write hello world in place of text, it will send you the hello world as a data. But it does it because of the HTTP bin server, so it actually goes and do the same number of steps.
100xEngineers: Which means that, it…
100xEngineers: uses the endpoint, it goes through the endpoint that we have seen, and what we have discussed. It has a request URL. It uses a method. In this case, it's using the get method, because we have mentioned the get method in the URL. It sends the body in the parameter, so this is the body which it is sending, and is getting the response back.
100xEngineers: Now, your job is to make sure that you get the same input, just like what we got in the first exercise.
100xEngineers: Here. So you need to make one small change in this part.
100xEngineers: Now, what that changes, I won't tell you right now. I'll give you, like, a minute or so to figure it out.
100xEngineers: But the goal is to take the same part, And,
100xEngineers: output the same part, but using the API.
100xEngineers: Go to the exercise number 3, just to repeat for everybody else. Go to the exercise number 3.
100xEngineers: Your job is to…
100xEngineers: give the same output back, which is there. Like, first you can do the clear, and maybe you can, like, mention any text here.
100xEngineers: Could be Hello World, but I would, like, prefer you to do this text, which was already written. This is the actual input which Ara will write.
100xEngineers: And the thing why we started this entire lecture is so that we can learn how to connect a whole system, which we can build for RF, especially what I am building as part of my whole document. So I did my discovery, and I want RF to write something like this. So, I'm testing my UI, I built UI, but now I want to test the API connection. I just learned how to
100xEngineers: connect with an API, how to call an API, by putting this URL. Now I want to connect this.
100xEngineers: In order for me to connect this.
100xEngineers: what is the change I need to make here in this URL?
100xEngineers: And I don't want you to generate everything, but just make sure that it gives you the output here, because if you generate right now, and let's say if I put the input, this is my user interface, I put the input here.
100xEngineers: And I click on Submit.
100xEngineers: It will run all these steps.
100xEngineers: Hopefully, you can also see on your page.
100xEngineers: In my case, the text was already pre-written here.
100xEngineers: Because of my browser cache, it didn't good.
100xEngineers: It was actually like this.
100xEngineers: But I think for all of you, if you remove the browser cache, let me refresh this.
100xEngineers: But harder to preload.
100xEngineers: So this is… this is what you're supposed to do here.
100xEngineers: If you put your text here, and then you will write the submit button, Then automatically, it will…
100xEngineers: Okay, right now it got a small error. How many of you got the error?
100xEngineers: How many of you got the response back?
100xEngineers: How many of you got the same error?
100xEngineers: If you got the same error, Try starting with Hello World.
100xEngineers: And let me know if you… if you… if you got the error resolved or not.
100xEngineers: Try writing, maybe, like, hello hyphen world, without any spaces.
100xEngineers: Just do this, and maybe we'll start with this.
100xEngineers: In this case, it should… it should give you a status 200.
100xEngineers: Let me know if you guys got this.
100xEngineers: How many of you got it? Can we have a quick raise of hand? How many of you got the hello world from this? Both in the output, as well as here? You can confirm whether you actually received the hello world from the API, because this will tell you the status. And the status is actually for that, like, 200 means everything is okay. Awesome! So…
100xEngineers: Congratulations to all of you, and what we saw right now is actually purposefully designed, because this happens a lot.
100xEngineers: when you send somebody or some information to internet, especially to an API, deterministic system, as I said, right? Machines don't understand the intent, so it can make mistakes.
100xEngineers: But that was the goal, to see, like, where it makes mistake and where it actually gets the,
100xEngineers: the information.
100xEngineers: You can try and you can play around with this tonight, and you can give me, like, the whole report.
100xEngineers: Of where exactly this API failed, and what is your guess why this API failed.
100xEngineers: And where it succeeded, right?
100xEngineers: The last part of this exercise is, actually, it's the second last part, which is…
100xEngineers: Where, instead of doing the git.
100xEngineers: we'll make the post request. This is where we start adding things, right?
100xEngineers: I'll change the text here. Something which you'll realize is that this… this format has changed right now. Earlier, it was…
100xEngineers: one single line, but right now the method has changed from get to post, and now we have a lot of things there. This is the JSON format.
100xEngineers: Right, so this is the same thing which we discussed. We established a JSON language, and now we are deciding the input and output. So we are sending input to this API as part of this JSON text. And because this is how JSON works with key-value pair, so we need to mention the text and the value of the text.
100xEngineers: So if I send this… I should be able to… Get something. Let's see.
100xEngineers: Okay, my status right now is 200, which means…
100xEngineers: the API worked for me, and this is the response which API got. The data was text, and I can confirm this. This is the exact data which I sent.
100xEngineers: It's in the JSON format, so it's the same thing.
100xEngineers: But right now, the thing which I tested is the POST method, as compared to the previous exercise, which is the number 3, we were testing the GET method.
100xEngineers: One more interesting part of the exercise is…
100xEngineers: what kind of fields you want to pull out on the output, because there's multiple things which are coming as a response. This is a raw response of the API.
100xEngineers: when we did this thing, this is the raw response which it gets. So it has, like, multiple things. For some people, only relevant information is text, but for some other people, maybe you want to get something else. You can read this entire document, and when you read this entire document.
100xEngineers: you can also fetch the relevant things. The best part about JSON, as I said, it's a file format, which is used for programming, so you can extract the each and every key-value pair. By default, everything is JSON.
100xEngineers: And, like, actually, this is the part which is coming in, so JSON slash text. And if tomorrow, like, if you want, like, something different, you want, like, URL, so you can also, like, directly get the URL part from it. So you can change this text feed. Not necessarily for the exercise, but just to tell you guys that
100xEngineers: This is how you read the JSON file.
100xEngineers: with key and value pairs. The reason why it is giving us this answer is because when we make this API call, it gives the response back, and in this response, we find where is the JSON key.
100xEngineers: And where is the .txt? Which is… JSON.txt means there should be a key inside JSON, and then we need to get the value of it.
100xEngineers: No.
100xEngineers: If you have done these exercises, and even if you had some errors doing it, it's completely fine.
100xEngineers: We'll continue doing more of the exercises, and it will get even more clear in the next lecture, because we will implement the exact same exercise in the API for both code and no-code. But before I leave, and before I give you the last part.
100xEngineers: This is where I want everything to…
100xEngineers: connect, and I want all of you to take away this last part. This is where
100xEngineers: We are coming to our…
100xEngineers: system, which I was promising you, right? Like, hopefully this will give you also clarity about
100xEngineers: exactly where the LLM connection lives, where the probabilistic system talks to the domestic system. This is the exact point.
100xEngineers: So far, we… we've been discussing about APIs, the contract, how one system talks to another system, we've tried different contracts, we understand different methods, the get, post, update, delete.
100xEngineers: Now it's time to, like, actually take a real API, which…
100xEngineers: Can help you to integrate a probabilistic system
100xEngineers: And the system which I want to recommend right now, which is open source and free to use for everybody, is known as Grok Cloud.
100xEngineers: We will be using this system throughout the LLM session for accessing the open source model, A, because it's the fastest inference which you can get for open source models right now. There are multiple providers also available. You can use that, feel free if you are using it for other part of the software. But for the exercise that we're going to do in the next lecture, I'll be using Grok Cloud. What Grok Cloud is, you can go to
100xEngineers: gropcloud.com.
100xEngineers: So, this is how the console looks like.
100xEngineers: You can sign up for this platform. It will give you free keys, so there are, like, some free limits, and… which are available for everybody, by the way, so you don't need to, like, recharge any credits for this.
100xEngineers: like, as long as you are not running infinite loops on your, Grok models, you can pretty much, like, cover all the exercises here.
100xEngineers: So, step number one, For the last exercise, which we are doing for this lecture.
100xEngineers: you need to go to Grok Cloud. Why we need to go to Grok Cloud? Because we're gonna connect our first LLM to the UI that we have built, or UI that we have in front of our screen.
100xEngineers: And the way how we're gonna do it is we have to find a provider, find a system, just like how we found the weather and the HTTP bin, and there's multiple systems. The step number one was understanding there needs to be a system on the internet, we know the URL. So we go to the URL, console.crock.com.
100xEngineers: go to the API keys. It's already mentioned, by the way, in the… In this…
100xEngineers: web page itself, if you go to… click on this link, consolegrok.com slash keys, continue with your Google account or GitHub account.
100xEngineers: it will lead you to this page. I have multiple keys, so you can click on this Create New API key.
100xEngineers: Click on this button, Create New API key.
100xEngineers: Write the name.
100xEngineers: Mention the expiry date. You can mention up to 90 days.
100xEngineers: I would recommend you to put the expiry date, because otherwise, sometimes the keys get lost, or sometimes you reveal keys somewhere. So it's better to, like, keep some type of expiry.
100xEngineers: Keep the expiry 90 days, and create your key. Mention the name of it. Once you create it, I won't create it right now, because it will reveal the key. It will give you a key like this.
100xEngineers: It should give you a key, like the GSK underscore dot dot dot, something like this.
100xEngineers: What you need is… Copy this key.
100xEngineers: And come back to… this part.
100xEngineers: Exactly here, you need to paste your API key.
100xEngineers: I already have it with me, so I'll paste it from my… pulled account.
100xEngineers: And when I paste it right now.
100xEngineers: And I want you to observe right now, you don't need to follow along for this part, I want all of you to pause and just look at my screen. So what I'm doing, we have started this experiment, right, with…
100xEngineers: An interface that we have designed, that we learned.
100xEngineers: this interface, we learned
100xEngineers: How can we connect it with a different system? And the reason why we did this whole exercise, so that we can derive the entire contract, the protocol of HTTP, what people throw it as a jargon, as a word, so we can derive and understand exactly why somebody has designed all of these things, why there's a URL, why there's a method, what this method is used for. So we derived everything from those principles.
100xEngineers: to set up a communication protocol with another machine on the internet, and we successfully did that. And we realized that this is how we can establish a set of rules so we can communicate it.
100xEngineers: Then we went ahead, and we said, okay, now we can try it with a weather API, we can try it with an HTTPIN API, but
100xEngineers: what we need, especially for my problem statement, is I need ARF
100xEngineers: to input one specific workflow, and I want the output so that it can generate a plan that identifies repeatable patterns. For this, I need a large language model. I need an LLM which can give me a plan.
100xEngineers: I need a large language model, it needs… it's a different system, same concept, so I need to first find a system. And I've done my research, so I'm recommending you, saving you some time. DropCloud is a system where you can find a lot of large language models which are open source, free of cost, available for everybody, with an inference that you can use throughout this program.
100xEngineers: So I'll use this system, and then…
100xEngineers: I'll use everything which I learned today, the entire knowledge of APIs, and I'll connect this entire
100xEngineers: system of Grok Cloud with the front end that we have built. So that is the goal which we are doing… we're trying to do. So, the front end which we built, which was just a fancy front-end that was giving an input-output, now we are trying to connect the Grog Cloud because we learned how to
100xEngineers: work with APIs, and we… some of you have also called your first API, so this is a test. Can we actually connect something useful and make something out of it? This… the theoretical part of this lecture, which we… some people thought was a theory, but it's not theory, actually. This is how the API design looks like.
100xEngineers: Which is a very well-paid job, by the way. A lot of people, do this, like, at a very senior level right now, to understand what are the inputs, output design in API, and connect a different resource.
100xEngineers: I hope you got why we're doing it.
100xEngineers: to connect to Grok API, because Grok is a service which uses a large language model, so it needs authentication, and that's why we need to log in, and once you log in, you'll get a key so that you can pass on this key, and you can use this API to make API calls.
100xEngineers: Now, what kind of models you can get access to? Like, there are, like, multiple models available, GPT OSS120 billion, LAMA 3.1, LAMA 3.3, you can use any of these things. By default, what we are using is Lama 3.3 for this experiment. We…
100xEngineers: go back, we paste the API key.
100xEngineers: From my account, and this is the API request. Now, look at this. It's actually very interesting, because
100xEngineers: It applies every single principle that we have learned today.
100xEngineers: the request URL, the first thing we need.
100xEngineers: to communicate with the service, because it's a different service altogether, right? The URL. This is a URL. And there's a whole URL which is telling me exactly… we found it something similar to what ChatGPT also does, like slash chat. And after this, it gives us the authorization. Now, why authorization is something new here is because
100xEngineers: it needs my login ID. Instead of putting my password and email every time, that's where we create an API key, so that I don't need to, like, put my email password every time I need to make a call.
100xEngineers: Then the second thing is content type. This is application JSON.
100xEngineers: exactly the thing that we have discussed in the number 2. We need to set up a common language. So it is telling that Grok accepts JSON language, and that's what we're gonna do. The third part is the body. This is the input to the model.
100xEngineers: Because it's a… it's a POST request.
100xEngineers: And this request will give me a response, and this is the body of the request.
100xEngineers: Which I have. So…
100xEngineers: the input is gonna be the model first. I need to define the model, and I'm defining the model LAMA 3.370 billion parameter model. I can change this model right now, by the way. I can go to my Grok, and I can find the model name, the list of model names, and you can change the model, you can… whatever you find comfortable.
100xEngineers: You can mention this here. Right now, it's using Lama's 3.C 70 billion parameter, versatile model. Then the second input comes in, which is a message.
100xEngineers: The message has a role user, and the content is the input. And in this input, I need to put something. So I will put my input, which Arav is gonna type, diagnose my morning workflow, this is my morning workflow, looks like, I open Jira, check task, write a report, and send it on Slack.
100xEngineers: So I'll change this input.
100xEngineers: And I'll put the exact same query, what Ara will ask.
100xEngineers: And I use my token, and now I will submit it.
100xEngineers: And let's see if this works.
100xEngineers: We have the output.
100xEngineers: This output is coming from the Llama 3.3 model. Let's break down your morning workflow, identify potential areas, current workflows, this, observation, suggestion, potential areas for improvement, automation, it gave me some next steps.
100xEngineers: Now, how good the response is this? Only I'll get to know if I actually implement it. I can make it better, yes, I can do a lot more things, but what we just established and what we just implemented right now on this call.
100xEngineers: is… Everything that we have… Designed.
100xEngineers: we used this knowledge of API to connect
100xEngineers: to a whole new system with our UI that we have. So actually, I'll… Put this here.
100xEngineers: This was a LLM.
100xEngineers: This is a system which we have right now, all of you, by the way. Like, any of you who can go and do a sign-up, and I want you to do this exercise right now, and I'll take a pause on this lecture. This is the whole…
100xEngineers: a whole bit. I'll give you this as an assignment if you have not completed it right now.
100xEngineers: we have something ready with us. We can build an interface.
100xEngineers: both code and no code, guys. You guys have, like, at least tools. You can use Lavable, you can use, Gradio, Python. You can build an interface. You know how the API works, you can use the curl command.
100xEngineers: although we have only learned a very basic part of it, but all of you know how to design these APIs, all of you know how to connect with these APIs using curl command. That is a command that we will be using, or we were using here. This works with NATEN, this works with a lot of other softwares. Every single operating system which you use, Linux, macOS, Windows, everything has pre-built curl command installed, which means
100xEngineers: The same thing that you have written here, you can write it on any machine. If you can write it on any machine, you can connect it with any machine. So, this also gives you, like, very language-agnostic way of
100xEngineers: designing APIs. Tomorrow, if you want to convert this into a Python API, a JavaScript API, any 10 API, a no-code API, you can do that. This is the common thing which is gonna remain common, right, and which basically is also built on top of the same principles that we derived during the conversation that you were having in this chat.
100xEngineers: That is the system what you guys have right now, and I want you to check this system out, build a system like this. In the next lecture, we're gonna break it down, and we're gonna write the code for it with a code track, and for the no-code track, you guys will be using NATN, we'll learn how to use NATN, what is the N10 part, how do you build back-end workflows using it, and apply and connect all the APIs.
100xEngineers: I'll upload this on the LMS, this is the exercise. Now you need to design your own API.
100xEngineers: everything that you have learned today, before you wrap up the session, just, take this as a note. I'll upload this as a practice set for this week.
100xEngineers: What is a URL? What does the endpoint look like for your API? What are the methods you want to use? What is the input and output for each and every API? For Arav, I gave you an example today in this. I also shared the document, so you can check out those documents. There are, like, notes written there.
100xEngineers: You need to do this for your own API. The observation that you started with, write down the input and output. Think about how many APIs you need, think about how many methods you need for which operations, when you're creating something, when you're reading something, deleting something.
100xEngineers: if you need an LLM, you can use Grok LM, Grok Cloud LLM, and you can reconnect and try it out. Right now, you can do it only from the app which I shared, but by the end of next lecture, all of you would be able to have
100xEngineers: this entire system running on your PC, and you can design these kind of APIs and also implement it. This is the end of session. If you don't have any questions, you can wrap up. If you have any questions, I'll take a look and…
100xEngineers: We'll continue discussion.
100xEngineers: Yes, for the code folks, yes, we will connect this in our Gradio app, and we'll build the…
100xEngineers: Full stack system there.
100xEngineers: How does using different languages impact on security and exposure to threats?
100xEngineers: And fundamentally is APIR maximum density area for outside threads.
100xEngineers: This is, same, the interface questions, however, and to answer the first part of your question, no, it doesn't affect how many languages you use. There are systems which are basically using, like, maybe hundreds of languages. The only thing it affects is
100xEngineers: the maintenance and the overall cost you need, and sometimes that can become a bottleneck for you to maybe, like, have a team who can, like, test everything, and that can have an indirect effect on maybe security and vulnerability. So, from that lens, yes, but if you ask me just, like.
100xEngineers: as an answer, no, it doesn't affect a lot. If you have the right resources, if you have the team who can, like, write languages. You can build a system with different languages, although it's gonna be, like, very expensive for you. Like, unless and until you have a very good reason, I don't recommend that. So always pick
100xEngineers: a language, if you can use it for the maximum, say, services and maximum things, stick to that. That really reduces the overall cost, which also reduces the overall time it takes for you to test the application and do all those things.
100xEngineers: API is a maximum density area for outside threads.
100xEngineers: In a way, you are right, because it actually points out to the interface logic, right? And if you ask this question from the interface lens, this is the bridge.
100xEngineers: If you look at any kind of construction in real world itself, what is the weakest link?
100xEngineers: If there are two buildings, or maybe, like, two islands, the weakest link is always going to be a bridge, because this is the part which is connecting to two different islands, two different, like, let's say, roads, or maybe two different buildings.
100xEngineers: In every interface.
100xEngineers: API, or maybe every interface in this system is a bridge. So, from that lens, yeah, the observation is correct. This is also an area where it can break, people can, like, enter in, because if I expose my app via an API,
100xEngineers: anyone can have access to it if I publish it on the internet with a URL. Now, I need to be make sure… I need to be, I would say, aware that people can reach out to this API.
100xEngineers: if I'm ChatGPT, I want people to reach out to my API because they are paying for it, but I also need to make sure that they are using it in an ethical manner. Nobody is exchanging anything from me, like, overusing resources.
100xEngineers: So that also becomes a thing. So it's… from that logic, it's… it's… you're right, yeah, from… from that observation.
100xEngineers: Can we share the no-code lecture now as well? It helps to see both approaches side by side for learning on both sides, please.
100xEngineers: Actually, you need to talk to my team. I need to check with them, because we do upload the lectures for everybody, so we are not, like, restricting the code and no-code lectures for
100xEngineers: only the people who operate for, you will get the access to all the recordings, irrespective of whatever track you have chosen. For example, you have chosen the code track, you will get the recording of the note code as well. If you've chosen a note code, you will get a recording of the code.
100xEngineers: But I'll check with my team exactly how you can access the recordings.
100xEngineers: Where do these open source models resides?
100xEngineers: When I call the LM and I send the data to an instance stored and maintained by the Grok Cloud. Yes, so Grok Cloud has bought
100xEngineers: GPUs and CPUs, and actually they have bought something called LPU, which is their own proprietary chip, so it is getting stored there. Grokloud is also acquired by NVIDIA, very interesting acquisition, by the way. So…
100xEngineers: I love this story because I think when I was reading about this, this happened in, like, maybe 6 months ago,
100xEngineers: Actually, this was, like, a whole deal which NVIDIA did.
100xEngineers: a $20 billion licensing deal for the Groc inference technology, and hire its senior engineering team. It's more like an aqua hiring, but
100xEngineers: they still have the independent part, but now NVIDIA has all the license, so it's a $20 billion, I would say, the licensing slash acquisition deal, which made this company… it was, like, a fairly young company. I think they… before that, they… they had, like, 4 to 5 years of, like, run… run rate as a startup.
100xEngineers: And I think, like, within, like, 5 years, they went… and it's, like, one of those companies, right, which is, like, nobody's aware about, like, what they are doing, but they were very focused on, we're gonna solve the problems, and we know that GPUs are expensive.
100xEngineers: So they built something called LPU, which is a Language Processing Unit, which is a… even a specific type of GPU that only processes language models.
100xEngineers: that was their whole, I would say the unfair advantage, or USP. So they said, okay, I'm gonna only focus on language models. And you won't find diffusion models here, you won't find, like, video models here, this is only language models.
100xEngineers: And the reason why they did this is because they want the maximum, efficiency, as well as the cost and the speed. So this is one of the fastest inference, as I said. If you're using for any real-time work, some of my people, like, students who have used this, they're using it for, like, real-time navigation systems, real-time, like, voice systems, so it's…
100xEngineers: It's a great platform, from that angle.
100xEngineers: But, to answer your question, it runs on Grok Cloud's, servers.
100xEngineers: on LPU specifically.
100xEngineers: For the no-code folks, what is the impact of knowing this? Because no-code folks are just leaving the code part to the LMs.
100xEngineers: No, actually, you're not, Aaron. You are not, you will learn this in exactly next lecture. That's why I said this lecture, the goal is to help you see the whole system, how it comes together, how it connects, and what are the principles of API, how you can design one, and how you can connect one.
100xEngineers: In the next lecture, we're gonna implement all of this. You will implement it using NATEN, and people who will be working with code, they'll be using it, they'll be implementing it using Python.
100xEngineers: So, no, you will not leave all the parts to LLM.
100xEngineers: I'll make sure that you guys will build these workflows, you will connect these APIs by hand.
100xEngineers: Otherwise, what's the point of learning all of this?
100xEngineers: Yes, Grok is free. Grok has a free tier. They have, like, certain limits, but you can, like, use it for free. Like, from last 3 years, I've been using Grok to teach, like, every cohort, and we have not, like, I would say, faced any restrictions as of now.
100xEngineers: you can use their free API and production app as well. You just need to make sure the rate limits, because you can't, again, abuse somebody's resources. Grok is right now, like, subsidizing it because they have the funds, so they give you the free tier, but let's say if you have, like, maybe every day, thousands of people inferencing
100xEngineers: Maybe having, like, hundreds of thousands of tokens.
100xEngineers: then you definitely need to, like, pay for those tokens, right? But a free tier is, like, very generous. So, Yasir, you can definitely use that to learn everything, and to build all the applications. In production, you have to, like, pay for it. The pricing plan is also very straightforward, by the way. You can check out the pricing plan on their page.
100xEngineers: Yes, Agar, actually, I'll… Let me stop my screen share.
100xEngineers: Yes, Adler, you have a question.
Sagar Batra: Hey, Sid, hi, good evening, how's it going?
100xEngineers: Good evening, man. How's it going? All good?
Sagar Batra: Thank you so much for another, foundational lecture, firstly. And, just to, you know, quickly reiterate, I'm not sure if you've gone through, the…
100xEngineers: I've gone through the message, yes, yes, yes, I've gone through that.
Sagar Batra: See, from a fundamental point, see, I've been somebody who has the domain expertise. Yesterday's session, had it been the case that we… I don't actually want to talk about yesterday's session, but it's just the principles bit, right? The UI, we didn't get the chance to build any UI yesterday, so even though… even though we learned the API
Sagar Batra: Fundamentals and the principles today, There's still, like, a missing piece.
Sagar Batra: Which is UI entirely, right? The yesterday session, at least the principles. So, had it been, let's say, a little bit principles of design systems, we would have immediately implemented it. So, I've been somebody who's very, you know, accurate with respect to his skill.
Sagar Batra: I've built the scale, I'm exactly at par with the current session, that is expected. It just is those missing pieces are some things that are knowledge gaps entirely. I've been somebody who's built design systems before.
Sagar Batra: So, hence, I could, you know, fill in those gaps, but then, like, principles of API that we learned today, I think something on those lines that we could do… I think Shefali just now mentioned this, right?
Sagar Batra: If we can have the access to both code and no code. Because my personal intent here is to actually fill that foundational gap.
Sagar Batra: If that is a possibility, Sunil said, that'll be, like, really, really helpful.
100xEngineers: Sure, why not? Like, I'll talk to my team, like, we could… we anyways, like, share the recording with everybody, but, yeah, I just need to make sure, operationally, whether it is possible on the LMS or not. If not, then we'll figure out something, yeah.
Sagar Batra: Sure, thank you so much, thank you.
100xEngineers: Also, on the other side, just to answer the first part of your question, I watched the recording of yesterday's session, and I know I had a conversation with Abhishek, so I read your message last night only, and
100xEngineers: I already, like, mentioned this, so we have a follow-up session for you guys specifically, to do an exact UI building part, which was missing in the last week's lecture. So yeah, I think we have basically incorporated for the feedback, and again, thank you so much, and I really respect and,
100xEngineers: love the way how you guys are, like, shaping the entire cohort experience, because I know this is also, for us, it's like a very early stage part.
100xEngineers: of, like, teams and the things which you are doing. So, yeah, I tell everybody that, yeah, please do share the feedback, like, whether it's good or bad, it helps us to, like, improve the experience. So, thank you so much, yeah.
100xEngineers: Can you please go to the last slide you were showing, whether I need to change? Okay, I will show you the last slide. This was the assignment slide, by the way.
100xEngineers: Let me share this. I'll anyways upload the assignment on the LMS, but just to…
100xEngineers: This is the last slide.
100xEngineers: You need to design your own API. This is what I was saying. Everything, what you have done until this point, where you had the observation, you took that observation into a hypothesis, you now understand how to grab the inputs and output for it, and design a UI, and maybe design now APIs.
100xEngineers: Now, you have to, like, write down how many APIs you need for your application, which you are building. Now, the thing is, this has a prerequisite, which means that you have finished the validation exercises.
100xEngineers: If not, then I would focus you to first finish that, and only perform this practice set when you have the validation with you, when you have the hypothesis with you.
100xEngineers: But once you have done that, then come to this practice set and design the APIs for it, just like what we have done for the hour of today. Write everything, the methods, the URLs, the endpoints, what do you need, what is the input for each and every API, what is the output.
100xEngineers: And once you write all of these things down, you can send it to us, you can post it on the Discord, and you can discuss this in the next office hour.
100xEngineers: I'll tell mentors that you'll get feedback on your API design, so don't miss the next session, especially for the next office hour, because
100xEngineers: I would recommend you to, like, design your APIs and get it reviewed by the mentors, and make use of those sessions for, from the review perspective, so that you get the immediate feedback, what are things you can do better. Because by the time when you finish all of these exercises.
100xEngineers: next Friday, we're gonna take all these designs, and we're gonna implement it, and you'll have your full
100xEngineers: full-stack application ready with the APIs and the UI. That's the goal for next… this… this week, and
100xEngineers: if you have the full-star application with APIs, we just saw we can connect with Grok, so which also gives us, like, a very strong bench to build an application, an LLM wrapper.
100xEngineers: To solve the problem.
100xEngineers: What if we can't finish the interviews?
100xEngineers: by the end of June 6th.
100xEngineers: the only thing which you will have, then you won't be able to get the feedback, because I will… like, this is what we do at 100X. We have, like, limited bandwidth of our mentors and of our instructors, and we want to make sure that we help everybody, but
100xEngineers: Like, you can still submit it if the mentors and anyone who is reviewing your application, maybe they get the bandwidth available. We'll try to, like, share this feedback on the office hour.
100xEngineers: That's the one thing which you can do, but I would recommend you to, like, try to finish it. Even if you can't do all the 10 interviews, at least do one, because
100xEngineers: I don't, I don't know, like, what's the…
100xEngineers: what's the easiest thing than, like, doing, like, one interview? Because even with one interview, at least you'll have some… some information. So, instead of, like, skipping the entire part, I would recommend to, like, do the number of interviews you can do.
100xEngineers: The more, the better it is, but if you can't do anything, at least talk to one person, and get the insights, and submit it, so that you have something ready.
100xEngineers: And it's okay, this is not the most…
100xEngineers: I would say the most interesting problem statement you are doing right now. The idea will change, the problem will evolve over the time, but the whole point of this is learning
100xEngineers: the journey of it, right? How to discover the problem, diagnose the workflow, understand what are the inputs and outputs in this workflow, how do we solve the problem which is worth solving, and then design everything and implement everything which we are learning here.
100xEngineers: So, that's what my recommendation is.
100xEngineers: Yeah, you need to change, the HTML for Olama. I've not introduced Olama right now, PK, so…
100xEngineers: I'll introduce this in the LLM session, so we'll learn more about local models, like cloud models, and I have a whole session for this, so I'll discuss that in detail, yeah.
100xEngineers: Cool, awesome. Thank you so much, guys, and I'll take a leave right now. As I said, finish this exercise, make sure you design your APIs, get it reviewed by your mentors this week, and let's implement this by the next week. By the next Saturday, I want all of you to have
100xEngineers: your first full-stack app up and ready. So that's the goal.
100xEngineers: And, keep building. I'll see you soon. Thank you so much.